Sentence,Sentiment,entities
"The GeoSolutions technology will leverage Benefon 's GPS solutions by providing Location Based Search Technology , a Communities Platform , location relevant multimedia content and a new and powerful commercial model .",positive,"[('GeoSolutions', 'ORG'), ('Benefon', 'PERSON'), ('Location Based Search Technology', 'ORG')]"
"$ESI on lows, down $1.50 to $2.50 BK a real possibility",negative,"[('ESI', 'ORG'), ('1.50', 'MONEY'), ('2.50', 'MONEY'), ('BK', 'ORG')]"
"For the last quarter of 2010 , Componenta 's net sales doubled to EUR131m from EUR76m for the same period a year earlier , while it moved to a zero pre-tax profit from a pre-tax loss of EUR7m .",positive,"[('the last quarter of 2010', 'DATE'), ('Componenta', 'GPE'), ('EUR131', 'PERSON'), ('the same period a year earlier', 'DATE'), ('zero', 'CARDINAL')]"
"According to the Finnish-Russian Chamber of Commerce , all the major construction companies of Finland are operating in Russia .",neutral,"[('Finnish', 'NORP'), ('Finland', 'GPE'), ('Russia', 'GPE')]"
"The Swedish buyout firm has sold its remaining 22.4 percent stake , almost eighteen months after taking the company public in Finland .",neutral,"[('Swedish', 'NORP'), ('22.4 percent', 'PERCENT'), ('almost eighteen months', 'DATE'), ('Finland', 'GPE')]"
$SPY wouldn't be surprised to see a green close,positive,"[('SPY', 'ORG')]"
Shell's $70 Billion BG Deal Meets Shareholder Skepticism,negative,"[('Shell', 'ORG'), ('$70 Billion', 'MONEY')]"
"SSH COMMUNICATIONS SECURITY CORP STOCK EXCHANGE RELEASE OCTOBER 14 , 2008 AT 2:45 PM The Company updates its full year outlook and estimates its results to remain at loss for the full year .",negative,"[('SSH COMMUNICATIONS SECURITY CORP STOCK EXCHANGE', 'ORG'), ('OCTOBER 14 , 2008', 'DATE'), ('2:45 PM', 'TIME'), ('full year', 'DATE'), ('the full year', 'DATE')]"
Kone 's net sales rose by some 14 % year-on-year in the first nine months of 2008 .,positive,"[('Kone', 'ORG'), ('some 14 %', 'PERCENT'), ('the first nine months of 2008', 'DATE')]"
"The Stockmann department store will have a total floor space of over 8,000 square metres and Stockmann 's investment in the project will have a price tag of about EUR 12 million .",neutral,"[('Stockmann', 'ORG'), ('over 8,000 square metres', 'QUANTITY'), ('Stockmann', 'ORG'), ('about EUR 12 million', 'QUANTITY')]"
Circulation revenue has increased by 5 % in Finland and 4 % in Sweden in 2008 .,positive,"[('5 %', 'PERCENT'), ('Finland', 'GPE'), ('4 %', 'PERCENT'), ('Sweden', 'GPE'), ('2008', 'DATE')]"
$SAP Q1 disappoints as #software licenses down. Real problem? #Cloud growth trails $MSFT $ORCL $GOOG $CRM $ADBE https://t.co/jNDphllzq5,negative,"[('$SAP Q1', 'MONEY'), ('#', 'CARDINAL'), ('Cloud', 'PERSON'), ('$MSFT $', 'MONEY'), ('ORCL', 'ORG'), ('$CRM $', 'MONEY')]"
"The subdivision made sales revenues last year of EUR 480.7 million EUR 414.9 million in 2008 , and operating profits of EUR 44.5 million EUR 7.4 million .",positive,"[('last year', 'DATE'), ('EUR', 'ORG'), ('2008', 'DATE'), ('EUR 44.5 million', 'MONEY')]"
Viking Line has canceled some services .,neutral,"[('Viking Line', 'PERSON')]"
"Ahlstrom Corporation STOCK EXCHANGE ANNOUNCEMENT 7.2.2007 at 10.30 A total of 56,955 new shares of Ahlstrom Corporation have been subscribed with option rights under the company 's stock option programs I 2001 and II 2001 .",neutral,"[('Ahlstrom Corporation STOCK EXCHANGE', 'ORG'), ('7.2.2007', 'CARDINAL'), ('10.30', 'CARDINAL'), ('56,955', 'CARDINAL'), ('Ahlstrom Corporation', 'ORG'), ('2001', 'DATE'), ('2001', 'DATE')]"
$FB gone green on day,positive,[]
$MSFT SQL Server revenue grew double-digit with SQL Server Premium revenue growing over 30% http://stks.co/ir2F,positive,"[('SQL Server', 'ORG'), ('SQL Server Premium', 'ORG'), ('over 30%', 'PERCENT')]"
"According to L+ñnnen Tehtaat 's CEO Matti Karppinen , the company aims to deliver fish products to its customers a day earlier than it currently does .",neutral,"[('L+ñnnen', 'PRODUCT'), ('Matti Karppinen', 'PERSON'), ('a day earlier', 'DATE')]"
The company 's share is quoted on NASDAQ OMX Helsinki Rautaruukki Oyj : RTRKS .,neutral,"[('NASDAQ', 'ORG'), ('OMX Helsinki', 'PRODUCT')]"
Elcoteq SE is listed on the Nasdaq OMX Helsinki Ltd. .,neutral,[]
Two of these contracts are for turntable anode vibrocompactors that will be delivered to Gansu Hualu Aluminum Co Ltd and another unnamed costumer .,neutral,"[('Two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Gansu Hualu Aluminum Co Ltd', 'ORG')]"
"Aviva, Friends Life top forecasts ahead of 5.6 billion pound merger",positive,"[('Friends Life', 'ORG'), ('5.6 billion pound', 'QUANTITY')]"
"In stead of being based on a soft drink , as is usual , the Teho energy drink is made with fresh water .",neutral,"[('Teho', 'ORG')]"
The company plans to increase the unit 's specialist staff to several dozen -- depending on the market situation during 2010 .,neutral,"[('several dozen', 'CARDINAL'), ('2010', 'DATE')]"
The company closed last year with a turnover of about four million euros .,neutral,"[('last year', 'DATE'), ('about four million', 'CARDINAL')]"
Shire CEO steps up drive to get Baxalta board talking,positive,"[('Shire', 'ORG'), ('Baxalta', 'ORG')]"
Costco: A Premier Retail Dividend Play https://t.co/Fa5cnh2t0t $COST,positive,"[('Costco', 'ORG')]"
"The five-storey , eco-efficient building will have a gross floor area of about 15,000 sq m. It will also include apartments .",neutral,"[('five', 'CARDINAL'), ('about 15,000', 'CARDINAL')]"
"The first installment of the Cinema Series concludes with a profile of Finnish inventor Olavi Linden , whose personal artistic journey and work at Fiskars has led to dozens of design awards .",neutral,"[('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Finnish', 'NORP'), ('Olavi Linden', 'PERSON'), ('Fiskars', 'ORG'), ('dozens', 'CARDINAL')]"
All are welcome .,neutral,[]
"Stockmann and Swedish sector company AB Lindex entered into an agreement on September 30 , 2007 , whereby Stockmann , or a wholly-owned subsidiary of it , will make a public tender offer for all of Lindex 's issued shares .",positive,"[('Stockmann', 'ORG'), ('Swedish', 'NORP'), ('AB Lindex', 'ORG'), ('September 30 , 2007', 'DATE'), ('Stockmann', 'ORG'), ('Lindex', 'ORG')]"
"HUHTAMAKI OYJ STOCK EXCHANGE RELEASE , 16.9.2008 AT 13.32 Huhtamaki 's Capital Markets Day for institutional investors and analysts is held in Espoo , September 16 , 2008 starting at 13.30 pm Finnish time .",neutral,"[('HUHTAMAKI OYJ STOCK EXCHANGE', 'ORG'), ('16.9.2008', 'CARDINAL'), ('13.32', 'CARDINAL'), (""Huhtamaki 's Capital Markets Day"", 'ORG'), ('Espoo', 'GPE'), ('September 16 , 2008', 'DATE'), ('13.30 pm', 'TIME'), ('Finnish', 'NORP')]"
`` We are pleased to welcome Tapeks Noma into Cramo group .,positive,"[('Tapeks Noma', 'PERSON'), ('Cramo', 'ORG')]"
- Profit before taxes was EUR 105.9 82.7 million .,neutral,"[('EUR', 'ORG'), ('105.9 82.7 million', 'MONEY')]"
Royal Dutch Shell to Buy BG Group for Nearly $70 Billion,positive,"[('Royal Dutch Shell', 'ORG'), ('Buy BG Group', 'ORG'), ('Nearly $70 Billion', 'MONEY')]"
"FinancialWire tm is not a press release service , and receives no compensation for its news , opinions or distributions .",neutral,"[('FinancialWire', 'ORG')]"
ASSA ABLOY Kaupthing Bank gave a ` neutral ' recommendation and a share price target of 174 crowns $ 24.7 - 19 euro on Swedish lock maker Assa Abloy AB .,neutral,"[('ASSA ABLOY Kaupthing Bank', 'ORG'), ('174', 'CARDINAL'), ('24.7', 'MONEY'), ('Swedish', 'NORP'), ('Assa Abloy AB', 'ORG')]"
"The item included restructuring costs of EUR1 .6 m , while a year earlier they were EUR13 .1 m. Diluted EPS stood at EUR0 .3 versus a loss per share of EUR 0.1 .",positive,"[('EUR1', 'ORG'), ('a year earlier', 'DATE'), ('EUR13', 'GPE'), ('EUR 0.1', 'ORG')]"
In 2005 the bank posted a net profit of Lt 8.2 mn .,neutral,"[('2005', 'DATE'), ('Lt 8.2', 'PERSON')]"
$AAPL afternoon selloff as usual will be brutal. get ready to lose a ton of money.,negative,"[('AAPL afternoon', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('a ton', 'QUANTITY')]"
$TSLA recalling pretty much every single model X @cnnbrk got to short that even at work you jump in money trade,negative,[]
"Dolce & Gabbana has asked the European Union to declare Marimekko Corporation 's `` Unikko '' floral pattern trademark invalid , in a continuing dispute between the two companies .",negative,"[('Dolce & Gabbana', 'ORG'), ('the European Union', 'ORG'), (""Marimekko Corporation 's"", 'ORG'), ('Unikko', 'ORG'), ('two', 'CARDINAL')]"
InterContinental Hotels first-quarter global room revenue lags estimates,negative,"[('InterContinental Hotels', 'ORG'), ('first-quarter', 'DATE')]"
"According to Finnish pension insurance company Varma , Varma was the recipient of over two thirds of the revenue of the earnings-related pension cover that was under competitive tendering in Finland .",positive,"[('Finnish', 'NORP'), ('Varma', 'PERSON'), ('Varma', 'PERSON'), ('over two thirds', 'CARDINAL'), ('Finland', 'GPE')]"
"A portion , $ 12.5 million , will be recorded as part of its winnings in a prior patent dispute with Finnish phone maker Nokia Oyj .",positive,"[('$ 12.5 million', 'MONEY'), ('Finnish', 'NORP'), ('Nokia Oyj', 'PERSON')]"
"L&G still paying price for dividend cut during crisis, chief says",negative,"[('L&G', 'ORG')]"
The volume of investments in the two phases of the project is estimated at USD 300mn ( EUR 215.03 mn ) .,neutral,"[('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('EUR', 'ORG'), ('215.03', 'CARDINAL')]"
"Russia accounted for 9 % of the Lagardere magazine division 's revenue , or EUR 114.40 mn ( USD 148.11 mn ) in 2009 , the USA - for 18 % .",neutral,"[('Russia', 'GPE'), ('9 %', 'PERCENT'), ('Lagardere', 'ORG'), ('EUR', 'ORG'), ('2009', 'DATE'), ('USA', 'GPE'), ('18 %', 'PERCENT')]"
The company also estimates the already carried out investments to lead to an increase in its net sales for 2010 from 2009 when they reached EUR 141.7 million .,positive,"[('2010', 'DATE'), ('2009', 'DATE'), ('141.7 million', 'CARDINAL')]"
Profit of the accounting period was EUR 0.3 mn .,neutral,"[('EUR 0.3', 'ORG')]"
"The six breweries recorded a 5.2 percent growth in domestic beer sales last year to 270.21 million liters , from 256.88 million liters sold in 2005 .",positive,"[('six', 'CARDINAL'), ('5.2 percent', 'PERCENT'), ('last year', 'DATE'), ('270.21 million', 'CARDINAL'), ('256.88 million', 'CARDINAL'), ('2005', 'DATE')]"
"In August-October 2010 , the company 's result before taxes totalled EUR 9.6 mn , up from EUR 0.5 mn in the corresponding period in 2009 .",positive,"[('August-October 2010', 'DATE'), ('EUR', 'ORG'), ('9.6', 'CARDINAL'), ('EUR 0.5', 'ORG'), ('2009', 'DATE')]"
"Systeemitiimi 's sales and project resources will also be strengthened , director Paul Skogberg said .",positive,"[('Systeemitiimi', 'GPE'), ('Paul Skogberg', 'PERSON')]"
Tesco share price jumps as Q3 sales top estimates,positive,"[('Tesco', 'ORG'), ('Q3', 'PRODUCT')]"
The fine print is here .,neutral,[]
The price for logs has clearly improved from 2009 and also the price of pulpwood has gone up .,positive,"[('2009', 'DATE')]"
"Thus , SysOpen Digia has , in accordance with Chapter 14 Section 21 of the Finnish Companies Act 29.9.1978 - 734 , obtained title to all the shares of Sentera that are to be redeemed .",neutral,"[('SysOpen Digia', 'PERSON'), ('Chapter 14 Section 21', 'LAW'), ('Finnish', 'NORP'), ('Sentera', 'ORG')]"
Diluted earnings per share ( EPS ) fell to EUR 0.63 from EUR 1.71 .,neutral,"[('Diluted', 'ORG'), ('EPS', 'ORG'), ('EUR 0.63', 'ORG'), ('EUR 1.71', 'ORG')]"
"At 3:37 p.m. Eastern time , a block of 2,400 contracts changed hands at a bid price of $ 0.45 .",neutral,"[('3:37 p.m. Eastern time', 'TIME'), ('2,400', 'CARDINAL'), ('0.45', 'MONEY')]"
"Some of the most recent technology deliveries include refinery technology to Anrak Aluminium , an iron ore pelletizing plant to Tata Steel and iron ore sintering plants to Bhushan Steel .",neutral,"[('Anrak Aluminium', 'ORG'), ('Tata Steel', 'ORG'), ('Bhushan Steel', 'ORG')]"
$VIPS similar pattern like beginning of May. Did u sell? Same now..will go up much higher after this drop.,positive,"[('May', 'DATE')]"
The firm generated sales of 187 mln eur in 2005 .,neutral,"[('187', 'CARDINAL'), ('2005', 'DATE')]"
"Stora Enso has also had meetings with the labor authorities , Employment and Economic Development Centres and representatives of the government in order to find solutions .",neutral,"[('Stora Enso', 'PERSON'), ('Employment and Economic Development Centres', 'ORG')]"
AstraZeneca profit down as sales of stalwarts fade,negative,"[('AstraZeneca', 'ORG')]"
"RT @andrewnyquist Chartology: Yahoo: http://stks.co/1itr $YHOO  Crazy looking chart, but nearing breakout resistance line...",positive,"[('RT @andrewnyquist Chartology', 'ORG')]"
Most bullish stocks on Twitter during this dip. $YHOO $GDX $GOOGL $STZ $GOLD $EW $VZ $CELG $SBUX $SCTY more: https://t.co/iuZJelfwt3,positive,"[('Twitter', 'PERSON'), ('STZ', 'PERSON'), ('$GOLD $EW $', 'MONEY'), ('CELG', 'ORG'), ('SBUX', 'PERSON'), ('SCTY', 'PERSON')]"
"Finnish GeoSentric 's net sales decreased to EUR 939,000 in January-March 2009 .",negative,"[(""Finnish GeoSentric 's"", 'ORG'), ('January-March 2009', 'DATE')]"
"Cohen & Steers , Inc. : 5 534 626 shares representing 4.985 % of the share capital and voting rights .",neutral,"[('Cohen & Steers , Inc.', 'ORG'), ('5 534', 'CARDINAL'), ('626', 'CARDINAL'), ('4.985 %', 'PERCENT')]"
More staff has been recruited in Japan to further complement its network of close to 50 service locations in more than 20 countries worldwide .,positive,"[('Japan', 'GPE'), ('close to 50', 'CARDINAL'), ('more than 20', 'CARDINAL')]"
"Paper companies were in negative territories , with Stora Enso R shedding 1.62 pct to 12.73 eur , UPM-Kymmene down 0.80 pct at 18.64 eur and M-real B 0.18 pct lower at 5.57 eur .",neutral,"[('Stora Enso', 'PERSON'), ('1.62', 'CARDINAL'), ('12.73', 'CARDINAL'), ('UPM-Kymmene', 'ORG'), ('0.80', 'CARDINAL'), ('18.64', 'CARDINAL'), ('0.18', 'CARDINAL'), ('5.57', 'CARDINAL')]"
Kauko-Telko 's centralized administration will be dissolved and appropriate parts of it will be transferred to operating activities and Group administration by the end of the year .,neutral,"[(""Kauko-Telko 's"", 'ORG'), ('Group', 'ORG'), ('the end of the year', 'DATE')]"
Operating profit for the quarter April-June 2006 amounted to EUR182 .2 m on sales of EUR3 .62 bn .,neutral,"[('the quarter April-June 2006', 'DATE'), ('EUR182 .2', 'MONEY'), ('EUR3', 'GPE')]"
Atria chose the DeLight to attract consumers in the 25-45 age group to its Atria Fresh range of microwaveable meals .,neutral,"[('Atria', 'PERSON'), ('DeLight', 'PERSON'), ('25-45', 'DATE'), ('Atria Fresh', 'ORG')]"
"Finnish IT solutions provider Affecto Oyj HEL : AFE1V said today its slipped to a net loss of EUR 115,000 USD 152,000 in the second quarter of 2010 from a profit of EUR 845,000 in the corresponding period a year earlier .",neutral,"[('Finnish', 'NORP'), ('Affecto Oyj HEL', 'PERSON'), ('today', 'DATE'), ('EUR', 'ORG'), ('the second quarter of 2010', 'DATE'), ('EUR 845,000', 'ORG'), ('a year earlier', 'DATE')]"
US sanctions put Gazprom-Shell alliance plans in jeopardy,negative,"[('US', 'GPE'), ('Gazprom-Shell', 'ORG')]"
"Profit for the period was EUR 10.9 mn , down from EUR 14.3 mn in 2009 .",neutral,"[('10.9', 'CARDINAL'), ('EUR', 'ORG'), ('14.3', 'CARDINAL'), ('2009', 'DATE')]"
"Profit for the period was EUR 5.9 mn , up from EUR 1.3 mn .",positive,"[('EUR 5.9', 'PRODUCT'), ('EUR 1.3', 'ORG')]"
Operating profit fell to EUR 20.3 mn from EUR 74.2 mn in the second quarter of 2008 .,neutral,"[('EUR 20.3', 'ORG'), ('EUR', 'ORG'), ('the second quarter of 2008', 'DATE')]"
"However , sales returned to growth in April-June 2010 , CEO Pekka Eloholma said .",positive,"[('April-June 2010', 'DATE'), ('Pekka Eloholma', 'ORG')]"
Operating profit totaled EUR 18.6 mn or 8.3 % of net sales .,neutral,"[('EUR', 'ORG'), ('18.6', 'CARDINAL'), ('8.3 %', 'PERCENT')]"
"Changes in the market situation and tougher price competition have substantially reduced demand for bread packaging manufactured at the Kauhava plant , according to the company .",negative,"[('Kauhava', 'PERSON')]"
"In connection with the deal , Digia will employ 19 persons from Nokia in Oslo and in Silicon Valley in the USA .",neutral,"[('Digia', 'GPE'), ('19', 'CARDINAL'), ('Nokia', 'GPE'), ('Oslo', 'GPE'), ('Silicon Valley', 'LOC'), ('USA', 'GPE')]"
"The Brazilian unit of Finnish security solutions provider F-Secure signed up 1,500 new clients last year , online news source Reseller Web quoted the division 's commercial director , Vladimir Brand+úo , as saying .",positive,"[('Brazilian', 'NORP'), ('Finnish', 'NORP'), ('F-Secure', 'PRODUCT'), ('1,500', 'CARDINAL'), ('last year', 'DATE'), ('Reseller', 'ORG'), ('Vladimir Brand+úo', 'PERSON')]"
The fair value of the company 's investment properties went down to EUR 2.768 billion at the end of 2009 from EUR 2.916 billion a year earlier .,neutral,"[('EUR 2.768 billion', 'MONEY'), ('the end of 2009', 'DATE'), ('EUR 2.916 billion', 'MONEY'), ('a year earlier', 'DATE')]"
"Dealers said the share was largely hit by investor disappointment about a refining margin of just 9.48 usd per barrel for the quarter and the performance of its shipping unit , which saw EBIT drop to 5 mln eur from 20 mln eur a year amid a fall in volumes and tanker rates .",negative,"[('just 9.48', 'CARDINAL'), ('the quarter', 'DATE'), ('5', 'CARDINAL'), ('20 mln', 'QUANTITY')]"
"` It is a testament to the quality of our LTE solution and our commitment to the Japanese market ' , he added .",neutral,"[('LTE', 'ORG'), ('Japanese', 'NORP')]"
The companies ' aim is to finalize the negotiations and sign the contracts at the start of October 2008 .,neutral,"[('the start of October 2008', 'DATE')]"
"Metso Foundries Jyvaskyla Oy will discontinue production on this line by 30 September 2008 , the company said .",neutral,"[('Metso', 'ORG'), ('30 September 2008', 'DATE')]"
"A total six of the polled analysts rated M-real -- two gave `` buy '' - `` accumulate '' , three gave `` hold '' and only one gave `` sell '' .",neutral,"[('six', 'CARDINAL'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('three', 'CARDINAL'), ('only one', 'CARDINAL')]"
"In September 2010 , the Finnish group agreed to buy Danish company Rose Poultry A-S for up to EUR23 .9 m in a combination of cash and stock .",positive,"[('September 2010', 'DATE'), ('Finnish', 'NORP'), ('Danish', 'NORP'), ('Rose Poultry', 'ORG'), ('EUR23 .9 m', 'ORG')]"
$YANG Double bottom 5.2,positive,"[('YANG Double', 'PERSON'), ('5.2', 'CARDINAL')]"
Tesco share price down as grocer faces SFO investigation outcome,negative,"[('Tesco', 'ORG'), ('SFO', 'ORG')]"
$aapl news is becoming very bullish again http://stks.co/tMU,positive,[]
"GS Engineering will install the valves at a liquefied natural gas LNG plant it has built for UAE LNG extraction and gas plants operator GASCO in Ruwais , UAE .",neutral,"[('GS Engineering', 'ORG'), ('LNG', 'ORG'), ('UAE LNG', 'ORG'), ('Ruwais', 'GPE'), ('UAE', 'GPE')]"
The percentages of shares and voting rights have been calculated in proportion to the total number of shares registered with the Trade Register and the total number of voting rights related to them .,neutral,"[('the Trade Register', 'ORG')]"
"M-Real said there are ` no grounds ' for the rumors , which ` have been circulating in the market for some months . '",neutral,"[('some months', 'DATE')]"
"Lember said the matter was topical also in Estonia , where a bill has been drafted at the Social Affairs Ministry that would scrap old-age pensions on favorable conditions .",neutral,"[('Lember', 'ORG'), ('Estonia', 'GPE'), ('the Social Affairs Ministry', 'ORG')]"
- Moody 's said it gave P A1 long-term senior unsecured and P P-1 short-term debt ratings to Finnish lender Aktia Bank 's EUR1bn USD1 .4 bn euro medium-term note EMTN program of 25 March 2011 .,neutral,"[(""Moody 's"", 'ORG'), ('P-1', 'NORP'), ('Finnish', 'NORP'), (""Aktia Bank 's EUR1bn USD1"", 'ORG'), ('EMTN', 'ORG'), ('25 March 2011', 'DATE')]"
$TSLA recall,negative,[]
"The liquidity providing was interrupted on May 11 , 2007 when Aspocomp Group Oyj 's shares traded below 0.50 cent ( Aspocomp 's stock exchange release 11.5.2007 ) .",neutral,"[('May 11 , 2007', 'DATE'), ('Group Oyj', 'PERSON'), ('below 0.50 cent', 'MONEY'), (""Aspocomp 's stock exchange"", 'ORG'), ('11.5.2007', 'DATE')]"
Hargreaves Lansdown bucks weak markets to see assets rise 2.6 percent,positive,"[('2.6 percent', 'PERCENT')]"
"At 12.59 pm , the OMX Helsinki 25 index was 0.32 pct lower at 2,694.81 .",negative,"[('12.59 pm', 'TIME'), ('25', 'CARDINAL'), ('0.32', 'CARDINAL'), ('2,694.81', 'CARDINAL')]"
"The decision means temporary lay-offs of fixed duration at the company 's Nastola and Jyvaskyla units , in southern and central Finland , respectively .",neutral,"[('Nastola and Jyvaskyla', 'ORG'), ('Finland', 'GPE')]"
The value of the orders is over EUR 10mn .,neutral,"[('EUR 10mn', 'ORG')]"
Ms Laakso will be responsible for HKScan 's HR functions and for their development in all of the Group ` smarket areas .,neutral,"[('Ms Laakso', 'PERSON'), ('HKScan', 'ORG'), ('Group', 'ORG')]"
"Fiskars is also engaged in the global supply of marine and energy equipment solutions and services through its associated company , Wartsila Corporation .",neutral,"[('Fiskars', 'ORG'), ('Wartsila Corporation', 'ORG')]"
Aberdeen Asset Management Gains Foothold In China,positive,"[('Aberdeen Asset Management Gains Foothold', 'ORG'), ('China', 'GPE')]"
Finland 's dominating rail company VR is planning to set the infected passengers for long-distance trip in a separate carriage .,neutral,"[('Finland', 'GPE'), ('VR', 'WORK_OF_ART')]"
"In November , the Finnish government decreased its ownership in the company further to 31.1 percent from 38 percent .",neutral,"[('November', 'DATE'), ('Finnish', 'NORP'), ('31.1 percent', 'PERCENT'), ('38 percent', 'PERCENT')]"
"Finnish Exel Composites , a technology company that designs , manufactures , and markets composite profiles and tubes for various industrial applications , reports its net sales decreased by 0.6 % in the second quarter of 2010 to EUR 19.2 mn from EUR 19.3 mn in the corresponding period in 2009 .",neutral,"[('Finnish Exel Composites', 'ORG'), ('0.6 %', 'PERCENT'), ('the second quarter of 2010', 'DATE'), ('EUR', 'ORG'), ('19.2', 'CARDINAL'), ('EUR', 'ORG'), ('19.3', 'CARDINAL'), ('2009', 'DATE')]"
"Of Bavelloni 's and NST 's joint ventures , Bavelloni Tools , completes semiproducts that are produced in Italy into high-quality tools that will be sold under the DiaPol brand .",neutral,"[('Bavelloni', 'PERSON'), ('NST', 'ORG'), ('Bavelloni Tools', 'PERSON'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('DiaPol', 'ORG')]"
The tool is a patent pending design that allows consumers to lay out their entire project on a removable plate using multiple clear stamps of any kind .,neutral,[]
$GOOGL is a short below 740 into the upper BB and is overbought,negative,"[('GOOGL', 'PERSON'), ('740', 'CARDINAL'), ('BB', 'GPE')]"
"LIGHTS OUT Before curfew , curl up with the latest bestseller and treat your eyes to the perfect reading light from Luceplan .",neutral,"[('Luceplan', 'GPE')]"
"UPM-Kymmene Corp. , the world 's largest maker of magazine paper , on Tuesday reported a 19-percent profit drop as lower paper prices , higher costs and a strong euro hurt revenue .",negative,"[('UPM-Kymmene Corp.', 'ORG'), ('Tuesday', 'DATE'), ('19-percent', 'PERCENT')]"
The total value of the contract is some EUR 8 million .,neutral,"[('some EUR 8 million', 'MONEY')]"
"The prerequisite for inclusion in the program and for receipt of any gains is that key employees acquire Aspo shares to the amount determined by the Board in advance , in the maximum .",neutral,"[('Aspo', 'ORG'), ('Board', 'ORG')]"
Mr. Doring has been with Eaton since 1989 and acted as the Business Unit Manager for Eaton 's Power Controls Business Unit since January 2007 .,neutral,"[('Doring', 'PERSON'), ('Eaton', 'GPE'), ('1989', 'DATE'), ('Business Unit', 'ORG'), ('Eaton', 'GPE'), ('Power Controls Business Unit', 'ORG'), ('January 2007', 'DATE')]"
"The 250 sq m 2,691 sq ft store in Copenhagen 's premier shopping district was inaugurated today , further strengthening the company 's presence in Nordic capitals .",positive,"[('250 sq m', 'MONEY'), ('2,691', 'CARDINAL'), ('Copenhagen', 'ORG'), ('today', 'DATE'), ('Nordic', 'NORP')]"
"In the financial statement for the first quarter of 2010 , Tikkurila is reported under discontinued operations .",neutral,"[('the first quarter of 2010', 'DATE'), ('Tikkurila', 'PERSON')]"
"The world 's second largest stainless steel maker said net profit in the three-month period until Dec. 31 surged to euro603 million US$ 781 million , or euro3 .33 US$ 4.31 per share , from euro172 million , or euro0 .94 per share , the previous year .",positive,"[('second', 'ORDINAL'), ('three-month', 'DATE'), ('Dec. 31', 'DATE'), ('US$ 781 million', 'MONEY'), ('euro3', 'PERSON'), ('4.31', 'MONEY'), ('euro172 million', 'CARDINAL'), ('the previous year', 'DATE')]"
"Name of Applicant : Jot Automation OYName of Inventor : Mammila Tuomo , Piirainen Mika and Kellokoski MikaApplication No. : 2424-KOLNP-2008 ADate of filing of Application : 16-06-2008Publication Date : 30/01/2009",neutral,"[('Mammila Tuomo', 'PERSON'), ('Piirainen Mika', 'PERSON'), ('Kellokoski MikaApplication', 'ORG'), ('2424', 'DATE'), ('Application', 'ORG'), ('16-06', 'CARDINAL')]"
Netflix Grows Efforts To Create Loyal Customers $NFLX https://t.co/5QXBkoBphe,positive,"[('Netflix Grows Efforts To Create Loyal Customers', 'ORG'), ('NFLX', 'ORG')]"
"The OMX Nordic 40 OMXN40 index , comprising the 40 most traded Nordic stocks on the Nasdaq OMX exchange , closed down 0.87 % at 1,064.14 points on Thursday .",negative,"[('40', 'CARDINAL'), ('Nordic', 'ORG'), ('the Nasdaq OMX exchange', 'ORG'), ('0.87 %', 'PERCENT'), ('1,064.14', 'CARDINAL'), ('Thursday', 'DATE')]"
$AAPL nibbling on a small long via 525.. buying off 13min charts..,positive,"[('525', 'CARDINAL'), ('13min', 'CARDINAL')]"
The operating margin of Aker Yards Cruise & Ferries division went down from 8.3 % to 6.4 % in the first quarter of 2007 .,negative,"[('Aker Yards Cruise & Ferries', 'ORG'), ('8.3 % to 6.4 %', 'PERCENT'), ('the first quarter of 2007', 'DATE')]"
"$TYC just about to break out to new highs, lots of technicals looking great right now.",positive,"[('TYC', 'ORG')]"
"Eero Katajavuori , currently Group Vice President , Human Resources , will take a year-long sabbatical starting from October 1 , 2010 .",neutral,"[('Group', 'ORG'), ('Human Resources', 'ORG'), ('year-long', 'DATE'), ('October 1 , 2010', 'DATE')]"
"Whats up with $LULU?  Numbers looked good, not great, but good.  I think conference call will instill confidence.",neutral,"[('LULU', 'PERSON'), ('Numbers', 'ORG')]"
The adjustment measures will be carried out in phases to secure the delivery capability .,neutral,[]
"Alma Media Corporation Press Release 15 March 2010 TYRVAAN SANOMAT AND PAIKALLISSANOMAT BEING BOUGHT BY SUOMEN PAIKALLISSANOMAT Two local papers , Tyrvaan Sanomat and Paikallissanomat , appearing in Sastamala and its neighbouring municipalities , are to be bought by Suomen Paikallissanomat Oy .",neutral,"[('Alma Media Corporation Press Release', 'ORG'), ('March 2010', 'DATE'), ('TYRVAAN SANOMAT AND PAIKALLISSANOMAT BEING BOUGHT', 'ORG'), ('Two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Tyrvaan Sanomat and', 'ORG'), ('Paikallissanomat', 'ORG'), ('Sastamala', 'GPE'), ('Suomen Paikallissanomat Oy', 'ORG')]"
"Temporary lay-offs , affecting the entire workforce , will also be implemented .",negative,[]
"A meeting for the media and analysts will be held on the same day at 10:30 a.m. at Stonesoft Headquarters in Helsinki , Italahdenkatu 22 A. The Interim report will be presented by Stonesoft 's CEO Ilkka Hiidenheimo .",neutral,"[('the same day', 'DATE'), ('10:30 a.m.', 'TIME'), ('Stonesoft Headquarters', 'ORG'), ('Helsinki', 'GPE'), ('Stonesoft', 'PERSON'), ('Ilkka Hiidenheimo', 'PERSON')]"
"Finnish Sampo-Rosenlew manufactures approximately seven forest machines monthly , and about half of machines are exported .",neutral,"[('Finnish', 'NORP'), ('approximately seven', 'CARDINAL'), ('monthly', 'DATE'), ('about half', 'CARDINAL')]"
"Facebook, near a buy point last week, faces a different technical test today https://t.co/c72LLMpiNM $FB $AAPL $NFLX https://t.co/fPFbYTYPuY",positive,"[('last week', 'DATE'), ('today', 'DATE'), ('$FB $', 'MONEY'), ('NFLX', 'ORG')]"
"4 February 2011 - Finnish broadband data communication systems provider Teleste Oyj HEL : TLT1V said Wednesday its net profit rocketed to EUR4 .8 m in 2010 from EUR416 ,000 in 2009 and it lifted its dividend proposal .",positive,"[('February 2011 - Finnish', 'DATE'), ('Teleste Oyj HEL', 'PERSON'), ('Wednesday', 'DATE'), ('2010', 'DATE'), ('EUR416', 'ORG'), ('000', 'CARDINAL'), ('2009', 'DATE')]"
$FREE Ha Heeeeeere comes the pump! So glad I picked up 9K end of day! Get ready for the bull ride!,positive,"[('FREE Ha Heeeeeere', 'PERSON'), ('9K end of day', 'DATE')]"
"Finnish technology group Aspocomp Group Oyj ( OMX Helsinki : ACG1V ) issued its third quarter report on Thursday ( 13 November ) , posting an operating profit of EUR0 .4 m , as compared to a loss of EUR0 .5 m in the third quarter of 2007 .",positive,"[('Finnish', 'NORP'), ('Aspocomp Group Oyj', 'ORG'), ('third quarter', 'DATE'), ('Thursday', 'DATE'), ('13 November', 'DATE'), ('EUR0', 'ORG'), ('the third quarter of 2007', 'DATE')]"
"The building complex consists of high-quality office and retail space totalling 49,200 square metres , the company said .",neutral,"[('49,200 square metres', 'QUANTITY')]"
Finnish insurance company Fennia and Kesko Group are ending their loyal customer cooperation .,neutral,"[('Finnish', 'NORP'), ('Fennia', 'GPE'), ('Kesko Group', 'ORG')]"
The unit is planned to be operational during the second half of 2007 and in full stream in 2008 .,neutral,"[('the second half of 2007', 'DATE'), ('2008', 'DATE')]"
"ITG 's share in the deal is estimated at some 500,000 euro $ 627,000 .",neutral,"[('ITG', 'GPE'), ('627,000', 'MONEY')]"
The plant is expected to enter commercial operation by mid-2009 .,neutral,"[('mid-2009', 'DATE')]"
Aspo has also investigated the sales opportunities of Kaukomarkkinat 's electronics business .,neutral,"[('Kaukomarkkinat', 'ORG')]"
BG Group appoints new CEO one month early,neutral,"[('BG Group', 'ORG'), ('one month', 'DATE')]"
The acquisition will have an immediate positive impact on Aspocomp 's financial result .,positive,"[('Aspocomp', 'PRODUCT')]"
"Finnair 's passenger load factor , which measures the number of sold seats as a share of all available seats , dropped by 1.3 percentage points to 76.7 % in September .",negative,"[('Finnair', 'ORG'), ('1.3', 'CARDINAL'), ('76.7 %', 'PERCENT'), ('September', 'DATE')]"
RT @bman1 $LNG looks primed also $EGHT poised to run too...,positive,"[('RT @bman1', 'ORG'), ('LNG', 'ORG'), ('EGHT', 'PERSON')]"
It is also 7.7 pct above the 12-month volume weighted average price of the stock .,positive,"[('7.7', 'CARDINAL'), ('12-month', 'DATE')]"
Coke dividend - 3%. Google dividend - 0%. For passive income Coke takes it. $GOOG $KO https://t.co/QBsoWjxOST,neutral,"[('Coke', 'ORG'), ('3%', 'PERCENT'), ('Google', 'ORG'), ('0%', 'PERCENT'), ('Coke', 'ORG'), ('$GOOG $', 'MONEY')]"
"Profit before taxes was EUR 5.4 mn , up from EUR 3.6 mn a year earlier .",positive,"[('EUR 5.4', 'PRODUCT'), ('EUR 3.6', 'ORG'), ('a year earlier', 'DATE')]"
The subsidiary is setting up a facility for manufacturing high-density interconnection printed circuit boards or PCBs at Nokia 's special economic zone at Sriperumbudur near Chennai .,neutral,"[('Nokia', 'ORG'), ('Sriperumbudur near Chennai', 'ORG')]"
$CRM Sep 40 calls are +35% since entry #BANG http://stks.co/deDm,positive,"[('CRM Sep', 'PERSON'), ('BANG', 'PERSON')]"
"In January-June 2010 , diluted loss per share stood at EUR0 .3 versus EUR0 .1 in the first half of 2009 .",negative,"[('January-June 2010', 'DATE'), ('the first half of 2009', 'DATE')]"
Rapala said it estimates it will make savings of 1-2 mln eur a year by centralising its French operations at one site .,positive,"[('Rapala', 'PERSON'), ('1', 'CARDINAL'), ('French', 'NORP'), ('one', 'CARDINAL')]"
$VMW  Got a nice push today following small sweepers of May C this morning,positive,"[('VMW', 'PERSON'), ('today', 'DATE'), ('May C', 'DATE'), ('this morning', 'TIME')]"
That topped consensus forecasts for earnings of 0.21 euros a share .,positive,"[('0.21', 'CARDINAL')]"
R&D Loan ) .,neutral,"[('R&D Loan', 'ORG')]"
"In future , the company intends to look for know-how from outside the company and to cooperate with other actors in the sector .",positive,[]
"You need to be ready when the window opens up , Rosberg said .",neutral,"[('Rosberg', 'PERSON')]"
"More than 50,000 tonnes of asphalt mix will be used in the contract .",neutral,"[('More than 50,000', 'CARDINAL')]"
"PA ) , JPMorgan Chase and Co ( NYSE : JPM ) and Pohjoa Bank are joint lead-managers on the senior , unsecured deal .",neutral,"[('JPMorgan Chase', 'ORG'), ('NYSE', 'ORG'), ('JPM', 'ORG'), ('Pohjoa Bank', 'ORG')]"
$CTRP  breaking out here on good vol and a parser buy signal  ..noticed this on bob langs comments looking for 48 fast,positive,"[('48', 'CARDINAL')]"
"Sales in Finland decreased by 10.5 % in January , while sales outside Finland dropped by 17 % .",neutral,"[('Finland', 'GPE'), ('10.5 %', 'PERCENT'), ('January', 'DATE'), ('Finland', 'GPE'), ('17 %', 'PERCENT')]"
"The pulp production in Finnish Kemij+ñrvi will also be liquidated and about 1,100 employees loose their jobs .",negative,"[('Finnish', 'NORP'), ('about 1,100', 'CARDINAL')]"
Nordea was the cheapest also for a couple in their 30s with debt .,neutral,"[('30s', 'DATE')]"
"Jussi Pesonen , member of the Sampo Board since 2006 , will renounce his seat in Sampo Board .",neutral,"[('Jussi Pesonen', 'PERSON'), ('the Sampo Board', 'ORG'), ('2006', 'DATE'), ('Sampo Board', 'ORG')]"
"Tesla is recalling 2,700 Model X cars: https://t.co/8Z7BkVsTl9 $TSLA",negative,"[('Tesla', 'ORG'), ('2,700', 'CARDINAL'), ('Model X', 'PRODUCT'), ('TSLA', 'PERSON')]"
"Adjusted for changes in the Group structure , the Division 's net sales increased by 1.7 % .",positive,"[('Group', 'ORG'), ('Division', 'ORG'), ('1.7 %', 'PERCENT')]"
"Making matters more difficult , the company said it has been grappling with higher oil and gas prices , which have pushed up the cost of energy , raw materials and transportation .",neutral,[]
The amending of the proposal simplifies the proposed plan and increases the incentive for key employees to stay in the Company .,positive,[]
The solution will now be expanded to include all ground staff tasks .,neutral,[]
"Operating loss totalled EUR 3.2 mn , compared to a profit of EUR 7.2 mn in the third quarter of 2008 .",negative,"[('EUR', 'ORG'), ('3.2', 'CARDINAL'), ('EUR 7.2', 'PRODUCT'), ('the third quarter of 2008', 'DATE')]"
"On #FEDDAY looking for a sharp move up in equities $AAPL $HD $LOW $FB seeing $UVXY $TVIX getting hammered, even though market is down.",positive,"[('FEDDAY', 'PERSON'), ('$AAPL $', 'MONEY'), ('$LOW $FB', 'MONEY'), ('$UVXY $', 'MONEY'), ('TVIX', 'PERSON')]"
As a consequence the Works Council had withdrawn its petition to suspend the reorganisation .,neutral,"[('the Works Council', 'ORG')]"
CEO Erkki J+ñrvinen is happy with the company 's performance in 2010 .,positive,"[('Erkki J+ñrvinen', 'PERSON'), ('2010', 'DATE')]"
"Comparable net sales are expected to increase more than 10 % in 2008 , in line with group target .",positive,"[('more than 10 %', 'PERCENT'), ('2008', 'DATE')]"
"Following the transaction , Lundbeck has worldwide rights for nalmefene , excluding North America , Mexico , Turkey and South-Korea .",positive,"[('Lundbeck', 'PERSON'), ('North America', 'LOC'), ('Mexico', 'GPE'), ('Turkey', 'GPE'), ('South-Korea', 'GPE')]"
"The government started the sell-off last month , putting an 8 percent stake in TeliaSonera on the auction bloc .",neutral,"[('last month', 'DATE'), ('8 percent', 'PERCENT'), ('TeliaSonera', 'ORG')]"
"The report goes on to provide detailed profiles of ten leading European specialty chemicals companies , and brief profiles of other major players .",neutral,"[('ten', 'CARDINAL'), ('European', 'NORP')]"
The company expects its net sales for the whole 2009 to be at previous year levels .,neutral,"[('2009', 'DATE'), ('previous year', 'DATE')]"
"The company is headquartered in Sievi , Finland , and is listed on the Nordic Exchange in Helsinki .",neutral,"[('Sievi', 'GPE'), ('Finland', 'GPE'), ('the Nordic Exchange', 'ORG'), ('Helsinki', 'GPE')]"
"The Finnish company sold its UK operation - consisting of 50 staff in offices in London , Birmingham and Manchester - as part of a deal with Hampden in July 2001 for its European-wide property and casualty arm Sampo Industrial .",neutral,"[('Finnish', 'NORP'), ('UK', 'GPE'), ('50', 'CARDINAL'), ('London', 'GPE'), ('Birmingham', 'GPE'), ('Manchester', 'PERSON'), ('Hampden', 'ORG'), ('July 2001', 'DATE'), ('European', 'NORP'), ('Sampo Industrial', 'PERSON')]"
"In the building and home improvement trade , sales decreased by 22.5 % to EUR 201.4 mn .",negative,"[('22.5 %', 'PERCENT'), ('EUR 201.4', 'ORG')]"
"The Innova 2 building will be located close to downtown , in the immediate vicinity of Paviljonki and the travel center , and within walking distance from the heart of the city thanks to the trade fair bridge .",neutral,"[('Innova', 'PERSON'), ('2', 'CARDINAL'), ('Paviljonki', 'GPE')]"
"Finnish textiles and clothing group Marimekko Oyj posted a net profit of 7.99 mln euro $ 10.4 mln for 2006 , compared to 8.4 mln euro $ 10.9 mln for 2005 .",neutral,"[('Finnish', 'NORP'), ('Marimekko Oyj', 'PERSON'), ('7.99 mln euro', 'MONEY'), ('10.4', 'MONEY'), ('2006', 'DATE'), ('8.4 mln', 'QUANTITY'), ('10.9', 'MONEY'), ('2005', 'DATE')]"
The main strength of the cooperation project lies in merging the know-how of two large companies .,positive,"[('two', 'CARDINAL')]"
Shareholders have a right to put on the agenda of the AGM items that are within the competence of the general meeting .,neutral,"[('AGM', 'ORG')]"
Kazgiprotsvetmet and Outotec Finland have signed an agreement on strategic cooperation in the marketing and providing of minerals processing and metallurgical plants and related services in Kazakhstan and the surrounding countries .,positive,"[('Outotec', 'NORP'), ('Finland', 'GPE'), ('Kazakhstan', 'GPE')]"
"Due to the rapid decrease in net sales , personnel reductions have been carried out on a wider scale than initially expected .",neutral,[]
The government has instead proposed an exchange of the state 's stake in LMT to TeliaSonera 's stake in Lattelecom .,neutral,"[('LMT', 'ORG'), ('TeliaSonera', 'ORG'), ('Lattelecom', 'ORG')]"
Stora is due to release its fourth-quarter and 2009 full-year earnings on Feb. 4 .,neutral,"[('Stora', 'PERSON'), ('fourth-quarter', 'DATE'), ('2009', 'DATE'), ('Feb. 4', 'DATE')]"
Full-year operating result for 2008 was 3.6 million negative .,neutral,"[('Full-year', 'DATE'), ('2008', 'DATE'), ('3.6 million', 'CARDINAL')]"
$NQ got hit hard lower this AM --> looks like it has found support a 18.89 http://stks.co/s052z,negative,"[('18.89', 'CARDINAL')]"
"In 2008 , AVC Systemhaus had net sales of EUR 10 million USD 7.1 m .",neutral,"[('2008', 'DATE'), ('AVC Systemhaus', 'PERSON'), ('EUR 10 million USD', 'MONEY')]"
"The company has established a 3G base station at about 17,000 feet at the foot of Mount Everest that will enable mountain climbers at the 29,035-foot summit to surf the Internet and even send videos of their exploits .",positive,"[('3', 'CARDINAL'), ('about 17,000 feet', 'QUANTITY'), ('Mount Everest', 'LOC'), ('29,035-foot', 'QUANTITY')]"
We offer our customers solutions based on renewable raw materials .,neutral,[]
A survey conducted by Taloustutkimus for Sampo Life shows that companies are badly prepared to losing key staff members .,neutral,"[('Taloustutkimus', 'GPE'), ('Sampo Life', 'WORK_OF_ART')]"
"Antti Orkola , president of Kemira GrowHow 's Industrial Solutions unit , told Thomson Financial News the company has put off opening the mine as prices of phosphate have been ` quite depressed for a long time ' . '",neutral,"[('Antti Orkola', 'ORG'), (""Kemira GrowHow 's"", 'ORG'), ('Industrial Solutions', 'ORG'), ('Thomson Financial News', 'ORG')]"
The pretax profit of the group 's life insurance business increased to EUR36m from EUR27m .,positive,[]
We make available the following brand-new market analyses Cement - Pakistan Cement - Malaysia Cement - Taiwan Cement - Philippines These analyses give a clear overview of the actual situation and future outlook of the cement industry in some Asian countries .,neutral,"[('Cement - Pakistan Cement - Malaysia Cement - Taiwan Cement - Philippines', 'ORG'), ('Asian', 'NORP')]"
"The Company serves approximately 3,000 customers in over 100 countries .",neutral,"[('Company', 'ORG'), ('approximately 3,000', 'CARDINAL'), ('100', 'CARDINAL')]"
RT @alphatrends VMarkets Are Still Acting Weak http://stks.co/1agn  $SPY $QQQ $XLF $SMH $IWM,negative,"[('$SPY $QQQ $XLF $SMH $', 'MONEY'), ('IWM', 'ORG')]"
"Operating profit totalled EUR 30.2 mn , down from EUR 43.8 mn a year earlier .",neutral,"[('EUR', 'ORG'), ('30.2', 'CARDINAL'), ('EUR', 'ORG'), ('a year earlier', 'DATE')]"
"One of the installed elevators will be a double-deck elevator , which enables more efficient use of the building 's core space .",positive,"[('One', 'CARDINAL')]"
HELSINKI ( AFX ) - Outokumpu said it has agreed to sell the Hitura nickel mine in Finland to Canadian group Belvedere Resources Ltd for 10 mln eur worth of Belvedere shares .,neutral,"[('AFX', 'ORG'), ('Hitura', 'NORP'), ('Finland', 'GPE'), ('Canadian', 'NORP'), ('Belvedere Resources Ltd', 'ORG'), ('10', 'CARDINAL'), ('Belvedere', 'ORG')]"
Just went long $ILMN,positive,[]
`` Social networking and location-based service trends comprise a significant share of the Internet traffic today and are appealing to MID users .,neutral,"[('today', 'DATE'), ('MID', 'ORG')]"
A total 30 % of the order value was booked in the fourth quarter of 2009 and the remainder will be booked in the second quarter of 2010 .,neutral,"[('30 %', 'PERCENT'), ('the fourth quarter of 2009', 'DATE'), ('the second quarter of 2010', 'DATE')]"
Johnson Matthey share price slumps as company posts full-year results,negative,"[('Johnson Matthey', 'PERSON'), ('full-year', 'DATE')]"
There have not been previous share subscriptions with 2004 stock options .,neutral,"[('2004', 'CARDINAL')]"
AffectoGenimap builds highly customised IT solutions for its customers in Finland and the Baltic countries .,neutral,"[('AffectoGenimap', 'ORG'), ('Finland', 'GPE'), ('Baltic', 'NORP')]"
"The closing of the transaction is scheduled to take place on January 10 , 2008 .",neutral,"[('January 10 , 2008', 'DATE')]"
"However , the offering will probably not be made at the current valuation , which partly derives from the deal in which the company was merged into a stock market shell .",neutral,[]
"Operating result for the 12-month period decreased from the profit of EUR0 .4 m while turnover decreased from EUR5 .6 m , as compared to 2004 .",neutral,"[('12-month', 'DATE'), ('EUR5', 'GPE'), ('2004', 'DATE')]"
The administrators have indicated a need for 900 job cuts at the Irish insurer over the next 15 months .,neutral,"[('Irish', 'NORP'), ('the next 15 months', 'DATE')]"
Net sales in 2008 are expected to be on the same level as in 2007 .,neutral,"[('2008', 'DATE'), ('2007', 'DATE')]"
Technical indicators for the stock are bullish and S&P gives NOK a positive 4 STARS out of 5 buy ranking .,positive,"[('S&P', 'ORG'), ('NOK', 'ORG'), ('4', 'CARDINAL'), ('5', 'CARDINAL')]"
"Revenue for the quarter totaled 27.4 billion , down 2 percent from 28.1 billion in the fourth quarter in 2008 .",negative,"[('the quarter', 'DATE'), ('27.4 billion', 'MONEY'), ('2 percent', 'PERCENT'), ('28.1 billion', 'MONEY'), ('the fourth quarter in 2008', 'DATE')]"
N-Viro operates processing facilities independently as well as in partnership with municipalities .,neutral,[]
The number of bodily injury cases quadrupled in 2000-2006 .,negative,"[('2000-2006', 'DATE')]"
"According to Ringman , Finnish paper companies have acquired know-how and capacity in paper recycling , which has turned out to be a successful strategy .",positive,"[('Ringman', 'PERSON'), ('Finnish', 'NORP')]"
The company also said that in Poland a profitability program has been launched at the Oborniki steel frame and sandwich panel plant .,positive,"[('Poland', 'GPE'), ('Oborniki', 'ORG')]"
And U.S. energy executives say high steel prices are threatening energy exploration .,negative,"[('U.S.', 'GPE')]"
Tesco sales rise shows tentative recovery continues,positive,"[('Tesco', 'ORG')]"
"In Finland , the launch of tie-in sales of 3G mobile phones did not cause a dramatic rush in mobile retail outlets during the first few days .",neutral,"[('Finland', 'GPE'), ('3', 'CARDINAL'), ('the first few days', 'DATE')]"
$NUAN held up well after the big gains! Maybe we're finally on the move on this!!its still very undervalued and has major upside,positive,[]
"The company can be split into two parts over the coming months , with Essent owning and operating production and supply , and Enexis owning and operating the grid .",neutral,"[('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('the coming months', 'DATE'), ('Essent', 'PERSON'), ('Enexis', 'ORG')]"
Officials did not disclose the contract value .,neutral,[]
"London 's leading shares today jumped almost 100 points , or 1.7 % , as the market opened .",positive,"[('London', 'GPE'), ('today', 'DATE'), ('almost 100', 'CARDINAL'), ('1.7 %', 'PERCENT')]"
"In the third quarter of fiscal 2008 Efore swung to a net loss of EUR 400,000 versus a net profit of EUR 200,000 for the corresponding period of fiscal 2007 .",neutral,"[('the third quarter of fiscal 2008', 'DATE'), ('EUR 400,000', 'ORG'), ('EUR 200,000', 'ORG'), ('fiscal 2007', 'DATE')]"
"The group 's operating loss was EUR 0.8 mn , down from a profit of EUR 2.5 mn in 2004 .",neutral,"[('EUR 0.8', 'PRODUCT'), ('EUR 2.5', 'ORG'), ('2004', 'DATE')]"
The move was triggered by weak demand for forestry equipment and the uncertain market situation .,negative,[]
The combined company had pro-forma net sales of 140 mln euro $ 188.9 mln and an operating profit of 13 mln euro $ 17.5 mln for 2006 .,neutral,"[('140 mln', 'MONEY'), ('188.9', 'MONEY'), ('13 mln', 'MONEY'), ('17.5', 'MONEY'), ('2006', 'DATE')]"
Managing Director Kari Inkinen says that Sponda 's leasing operations developed highly favourably .,positive,"[('Kari Inkinen', 'PERSON'), ('Sponda', 'PERSON')]"
17 March 2011 - Goldman Sachs estimates that there are negative prospects for the Norwegian mobile operations of Norway 's Telenor ASA OSL : TEL and Sweden 's TeliaSonera AB STO : TLSN in the short term .,negative,"[('17 March 2011', 'DATE'), ('Norwegian', 'NORP'), ('Norway', 'GPE'), ('TEL', 'ORG'), ('Sweden', 'GPE'), ('TeliaSonera AB', 'ORG')]"
"$TSLA steaming up again, this stock is relentless at the moment",positive,[]
Marathon estimates the value of its remaining stake in Protalix at $ 27 million .,neutral,"[('Protalix', 'GPE'), ('$ 27 million', 'MONEY')]"
Whitbread share price climbs on Q4 sales growth,positive,"[('Whitbread', 'ORG'), ('Q4', 'ORG')]"
Incap Contract Manufacturing is a subsidiary of Incap Corporation of Finland .,neutral,"[('Incap Corporation of Finland', 'ORG')]"
"Operating profit totaled EUR 37,7 mn , up slightly from EUR 37.2 mn in the corresponding period in 2006 .",positive,"[('EUR', 'ORG'), ('EUR', 'ORG'), ('37.2', 'CARDINAL'), ('2006', 'DATE')]"
"We went to the market with yield guidance of the 7.25 % area , which gave us the flexibility to go up or down by 1-8th .",neutral,"[('7.25 %', 'PERCENT'), ('1-8th', 'DATE')]"
"RT @stockdemons think shorting here into close might be play, $SPY - high beta reversing..looks worth a shot",negative,"[('RT', 'GPE'), ('SPY', 'MONEY')]"
"VDW combined with LXE devices enhances productivity , enabling workers to use a single device to perform voice , scanning and keyboard functions .",positive,"[('VDW', 'ORG')]"
"Thus the method will cut working costs , and will fasten the planning and building processes .",positive,[]
Talentum 's net sales in September were smaller than expected .,negative,"[('Talentum', 'ORG'), ('September', 'DATE')]"
COPYRIGHT AFX News and AFX Financial News Logo are registered trademarks of AFX News Limited,neutral,"[('AFX News', 'ORG'), ('AFX Financial News Logo', 'ORG'), ('AFX News Limited', 'ORG')]"
$LNKD Daily Phase 2 retest - Price experiencing early rejection. Can it retest? http://stks.co/t04xX,negative,"[('LNKD Daily', 'PERSON')]"
RBS will reportedly appoint Howard Davies as its next chairman,neutral,"[('RBS', 'ORG'), ('Howard Davies', 'ORG')]"
"Tesco, Asda sales fall as march of the discounters continues-Kantar",negative,"[('Tesco', 'ORG'), ('Asda', 'ORG')]"
`` With this new version it is very important for us to introduce a BIM process that is based on the detailed building information model .,neutral,"[('BIM', 'GPE')]"
SAMPO PLC Jarmo Salonen Head of Investor Relations and Group Communications tel. +358 10 516 0030 Distribution : NASDAQ OMX Helsinki The principal media Financial Supervisory Authority www.sampo.com This announcement is distributed by Thomson Reuters on behalf of Thomson Reuters clients .,neutral,"[('SAMPO PLC', 'ORG'), ('Jarmo Salonen Head', 'PERSON'), ('Investor Relations and Group Communications', 'ORG'), ('10', 'CARDINAL'), ('516', 'CARDINAL'), ('NASDAQ OMX Helsinki', 'PERSON'), ('Financial Supervisory Authority', 'ORG'), ('Thomson Reuters', 'ORG'), ('Thomson Reuters', 'ORG')]"
.@barronsonline sees #Apple at $150/share in a year (+36% from today) on growing services business. $AAPL https://t.co/3BDNEKN7l1,positive,"[('Apple', 'ORG'), ('150', 'MONEY'), ('a year', 'DATE'), ('today', 'DATE')]"
Pharmaceutical market in Poland Global Research & Data Services published recently a market analysis about the pharmaceutical markets in Poland .,neutral,"[('Poland Global Research & Data Services', 'ORG'), ('Poland', 'GPE')]"
Altogether Finnair has canceled over 500 flights because of the strike .,negative,"[('Finnair', 'ORG'), ('over 500', 'CARDINAL')]"
"The employer , together with health personnel , supports quitting and pays part of the cost of nicotine treatments .",neutral,[]
Pretax loss totaled EUR 117mn compared to a loss of EUR 65mn in the corresponding period .,neutral,"[('EUR 117mn', 'ORG'), ('EUR 65mn', 'ORG')]"
The order includes 48 ship cranes that will be delivered for 12 container feeders to be built at Wenchong shipyard in China .,neutral,"[('48', 'CARDINAL'), ('12', 'CARDINAL'), ('Wenchong', 'ORG'), ('China', 'GPE')]"
"Copper , lead and nickel also dropped ... HBOS ( HBOS ) plummeted 20 % to 70.3 pence after saying this year+ó ??",neutral,"[('20 %', 'PERCENT'), ('70.3 pence', 'MONEY')]"
$GOOG Testing the 200 day after some consolidation http://stks.co/h0cPJ,positive,"[('http://stks.co/h0cPJ', 'ORDINAL')]"
"He joins Technopolis from KONE where he has held various positions within the Group , most recently as Director of Service Business and Business Development for KONE s Middle Eastern operations .",neutral,"[('Technopolis', 'PERSON'), ('KONE', 'ORG'), ('Group', 'ORG'), ('Service Business and Business Development for KONE s', 'ORG'), ('Middle Eastern', 'NORP')]"
"We succeeded in increasing our market share of sold apartment '' , comments Mr Kari Kauniskangas , Head of YIT International Construction Services .",positive,"[('Kari Kauniskangas', 'PERSON'), ('YIT International Construction Services', 'ORG')]"
"Profitability ( EBIT % ) was 13.9 % , compared to 13.1 % in the previous-year period .",positive,"[('13.9 %', 'PERCENT'), ('13.1 %', 'PERCENT'), ('the previous-year', 'DATE')]"
"Finnish GeoSentric 's net sales decreased to EUR 939,000 in January-March 2009 .",neutral,"[(""Finnish GeoSentric 's"", 'ORG'), ('January-March 2009', 'DATE')]"
"The plant is scheduled for completion in late February 2007 with hand over of some areas in January Two other suppliers of Nokia - Aspocomp Group Oyj and Perlos - have announced their plans to establish plants within the Nokia complex Together , they will invest Rs 365 crore .",neutral,"[('late February 2007', 'DATE'), ('January Two', 'DATE'), ('Nokia - Aspocomp Group Oyj', 'ORG'), ('Nokia', 'ORG')]"
- UPM-Kymmene upgraded to ` in-line ' from ` underperform ' by Goldman Sachs .,positive,"[('Goldman Sachs', 'ORG')]"
Slump in Weir leads FTSE down from record high,negative,"[('Slump', 'ORG'), ('Weir', 'GPE'), ('FTSE', 'ORG')]"
"Royal Mail 'breached competition law' over delivery service changes, Ofcom claims",negative,"[(""Royal Mail '"", 'ORG'), ('Ofcom', 'ORG')]"
"The cooperation will involve Arena Partners buying a 35 % share of the new joint venture company , operating in Alma Media 's home sales , vehicle and consumer advertising marketplace businesses .",neutral,"[('Arena Partners', 'ORG'), ('35 %', 'PERCENT'), (""Alma Media 's"", 'ORG')]"
The Efore plant at Saarijarvi in central Finland is one of the largest employers in the region .,neutral,"[('Efore', 'ORG'), ('Saarijarvi', 'GPE'), ('Finland', 'GPE')]"
However short-term rentals are becoming more popular .,neutral,[]
EMSA Deputy Chairman of the Board Juri Lember told BNS on Wednesday that this was the first time he heard about the strike as the Swedish side had not informed the Estonian union yet .,neutral,"[('EMSA', 'ORG'), ('the Board Juri Lember', 'ORG'), ('BNS', 'ORG'), ('Wednesday', 'DATE'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Swedish', 'NORP'), ('Estonian', 'NORP')]"
Tesco closes in on new chairman with Dixons Carphone's John Allan in the frame,positive,"[('Tesco', 'ORG'), (""Dixons Carphone's"", 'ORG'), ('John Allan', 'PERSON')]"
"The device offers multimedia performance along with a host of productivity applications , including live stock prices .",neutral,[]
"Sales climbed 19.2 pct to 1.002 bln eur , surpassing the 953 mln eur consensus figure .",positive,"[('19.2', 'CARDINAL'), ('1.002', 'CARDINAL'), ('953', 'CARDINAL')]"
$FB turns back down in early trading.... https://t.co/reuf5PzhBm,negative,"[('https://t.co/reuf5PzhBm', 'PERSON')]"
"Utah 's capital wanted to be the next U.S. headquarters of Amer Sports Corp. , a ski-equipment company .",neutral,"[('Utah', 'GPE'), ('U.S.', 'GPE'), ('Amer Sports Corp.', 'ORG')]"
Old Mutual First-Quarter Sales Up 18% Buoyed by Emerging Markets,positive,"[('First-Quarter', 'DATE'), ('18%', 'PERCENT')]"
"The dividend is payable on February 1 , 2010 to shareholders of record on January 19 , 2010 .",neutral,"[('February 1 , 2010', 'DATE'), ('January 19 , 2010', 'DATE')]"
"Sales in Finland decreased by 10.5 % in January , while sales outside Finland dropped by 17 % .",negative,"[('Finland', 'GPE'), ('10.5 %', 'PERCENT'), ('January', 'DATE'), ('Finland', 'GPE'), ('17 %', 'PERCENT')]"
"Furthermore , Bunge will also sign a licensing agreement for the Sunnuntai and Carlshamn Mejeri brands .",positive,"[('Bunge', 'ORG'), ('Sunnuntai', 'GPE'), ('Mejeri', 'NORP')]"
"KESKO CORPORATION STOCK EXCHANGE RELEASE 28.02.2008 AT 09.30 1 ( 1 ) Kesko Corporation and Aspo plc today signed an agreement by which Aspo acquires the share capital of Kauko-Telko Ltd , a subsidiary wholly owned by Kesko .",positive,"[('KESKO CORPORATION STOCK EXCHANGE', 'ORG'), ('28.02.2008', 'CARDINAL'), ('09.30 1', 'CARDINAL'), ('1', 'CARDINAL'), ('Aspo plc', 'ORG'), ('today', 'DATE'), ('Aspo', 'ORG'), ('Kauko-Telko Ltd', 'ORG'), ('Kesko', 'PERSON')]"
$LULU #Outlook #Q1 2013 #lost revenue in the range of $12 million to $17 million -not good,negative,"[('LULU', 'PERSON'), ('2013', 'DATE'), ('$12 million to $17 million', 'MONEY')]"
Mobile communication and wireless broadband provider Nokia Inc NYSE : NOK today set new financial targets and forecasts for Nokia and the mobile device industry and also for Nokia Siemens Networks and the mobile and fixed infrastructure and related services market .,neutral,"[('Nokia Inc NYSE', 'ORG'), ('NOK', 'ORG'), ('today', 'DATE'), ('Nokia', 'ORG'), ('Nokia Siemens Networks', 'ORG')]"
"POYRY PLC Additional information by : Heikki Malinen , President and CEO , Poyry PLC tel. +358 10 33 21307 Poyry is a global expert in consulting and engineering .",neutral,"[('POYRY PLC', 'ORG'), ('Heikki Malinen', 'PERSON'), ('Poyry PLC', 'ORG'), ('33 21307', 'DATE')]"
Danish company FLSmidth has acknowledged that it has violated a patent held by Finnish Metso .,neutral,"[('Danish', 'NORP'), ('FLSmidth', 'ORG'), ('Finnish', 'NORP'), ('Metso', 'ORG')]"
Amanda Capital has investments in 22 private equity funds and in over 200 unquoted companies mainly in Europe .,neutral,"[('Amanda Capital', 'ORG'), ('22', 'CARDINAL'), ('over 200', 'CARDINAL'), ('Europe', 'LOC')]"
"Net interest income was EUR 39.3 mn , up from EUR 32.7 mn .",positive,"[('EUR', 'ORG'), ('EUR', 'ORG'), ('32.7', 'CARDINAL')]"
"Jeder Beta-Tester erh+ñlt kostenlos sechs Monate lang Updates und hat laut eigener Aussage die M+Âglichkeit , die finale Version zu beeinflussen .",neutral,"[('M+Âglichkeit', 'PERSON')]"
"JP Morgan expects that Scala will lower Nobel Biocare 's growth forecast for 2007 from the current guidance of 23-25 pct , as well as the operating margin target from the current 34-35 pct .",neutral,"[('JP Morgan', 'ORG'), ('Scala', 'ORG'), (""Nobel Biocare 's"", 'PERSON'), ('2007', 'DATE'), ('23-25', 'CARDINAL'), ('34', 'CARDINAL')]"
Aviva promises higher dividends to boost flagging share price,positive,[]
"In addition , MIDs are always online and enable full Internet browsing .",neutral,[]
"Fiskars has a strong portfolio of international brands , which include Fiskars , Iittala , Gerber , Silva and Buster .",positive,"[('Fiskars', 'ORG'), ('Fiskars', 'ORG'), ('Iittala', 'GPE'), ('Silva', 'PERSON'), ('Buster', 'PERSON')]"
#Tesla: Model X Recall Adds To Reliability Issues $TSLA https://t.co/jVXQ4DoXnP,negative,"[('Tesla', 'PERSON'), ('Model X Recall', 'PERSON'), ('TSLA', 'PERSON')]"
The name of the buyer was not disclosed .,neutral,[]
Net sales of the Vegetable Oil Business rose to EUR 10.6 mn from EUR 10.1 mn .,positive,"[('EUR', 'ORG'), ('10.6', 'CARDINAL'), ('EUR', 'ORG'), ('10.1', 'CARDINAL')]"
"Under the agreement Benefon 's forthcoming range of TWIG integrated GPS navigation and mobile phone devices will use the jointly developed web-based tracking and location technology , in both consumer and commercial applications .",neutral,"[('Benefon', 'PERSON'), ('TWIG', 'ORG')]"
"Following this increase Huhtamaki 's registered share capital is EUR360 .62 m and the number of shares outstanding is 106,063,320 .",neutral,"[('Huhtamaki', 'ORG'), ('106,063,320', 'CARDINAL')]"
"The three year turn-around program is expected to ensure Salomon 's future competitiveness , the company said .",positive,"[('three year', 'DATE'), ('Salomon', 'ORG')]"
"In the autumn , it plans to expand service to St. Petersburg and Moscow and launch service to Yekaterinburg , Russia , flying there three times a week .",positive,"[('St. Petersburg', 'GPE'), ('Moscow', 'GPE'), ('Yekaterinburg', 'GPE'), ('Russia', 'GPE'), ('three', 'CARDINAL')]"
"The company 's profit totaled Ls 578,100 in H1 2007 , down 30.9 % year-on-year .",negative,"[('578,100', 'CARDINAL'), ('H1 2007', 'DATE'), ('30.9 %', 'PERCENT')]"
The Federal Secretary for Transport and Communication of Mexico has awarded Poyry and its Mexican partner Sintra a consulting contract in connection with the Buenavista-Cuautitlan suburban railway .,positive,"[('Transport and Communication of Mexico', 'ORG'), ('Poyry', 'PERSON'), ('Mexican', 'NORP'), ('Sintra', 'NORP'), ('Buenavista', 'PERSON')]"
FDA approves AstraZeneca drug for advanced lung cancer,positive,"[('FDA', 'ORG'), ('AstraZeneca', 'ORG')]"
The order is included in Metso 's fourth quarter 2007 order backlog .,neutral,"[('Metso', 'ORG'), ('fourth quarter 2007', 'DATE')]"
Lieksaare Oy has earlier been regarded under the control of Saarelainen Oy and the individual shareholders under the shareholder agreement .,neutral,"[('Lieksaare Oy', 'ORG'), ('Saarelainen Oy', 'ORG')]"
$mcp rolling over for a new intraday low. Bottom Pickers continue to get destroyed,negative,"[('mcp', 'PERSON')]"
The company has an annual turnover of EUR32 .8 m.,neutral,"[('annual', 'DATE')]"
It has80 branches in Finland with annual revenue in Finland of ?,neutral,"[('Finland', 'GPE'), ('annual', 'DATE'), ('Finland', 'GPE')]"
"The portfolio comprises of 118,000 m2 of leasable space with a vacancy rate of roughly 5 % , let to around 140 tenants of which two of the largest are the Swedish government and Ericsson .",neutral,"[('118,000', 'CARDINAL'), ('roughly 5 %', 'PERCENT'), ('140', 'CARDINAL'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Swedish', 'NORP'), ('Ericsson', 'PERSON')]"
WPP boosts sales despite cautious clients,positive,"[('WPP', 'ORG')]"
The medium-term operative targets of the company remain unchanged .,neutral,[]
"ADP News - Feb 13 , 2009 - Finnish retailer Kesko Oyj HEL : KESBV said today its total sales , excluding value added tax VAT , stood at EUR 661.3 million USD 853.1 m in January 2009 , down 15.2 % year-on-yea",negative,"[('ADP News - Feb', 'ORG'), ('Finnish', 'NORP'), ('Kesko Oyj', 'PERSON'), ('KESBV', 'ORG'), ('today', 'DATE'), ('VAT', 'ORG'), ('EUR', 'ORG'), ('January 2009', 'DATE'), ('15.2 %', 'PERCENT')]"
`` Consumers have very well received our packed fresh meat .,positive,[]
The corrected chapter is in its entirety below .,neutral,[]
"The major part of the deliveries include different AC and CXE amplifier solutions and products by DINH Telecom , a company acquired by Teleste last spring .",neutral,"[('AC', 'ORG'), ('CXE', 'ORG'), ('DINH Telecom', 'ORG'), ('last spring', 'DATE')]"
"TietoEnator itself uses Nokia 's Intellisync Mobile Suite 's wireless email , calendar , and device management capabilities , and the company will now extend these services to its customers .",positive,"[('TietoEnator', 'ORG'), ('Nokia', 'ORG'), (""Intellisync Mobile Suite 's"", 'ORG')]"
It will provide heating in the form of hot water for the sawmill 's needs .,neutral,[]
"However , the net sales declined to EUR 803.6 million from EUR 1.2 billion .",negative,"[('EUR 803.6 million', 'MONEY'), ('EUR 1.2 billion', 'MONEY')]"
"In the second quarter of 2010 , Raute 's net loss narrowed to EUR 123,000 from EUR 1.5 million in the same period of 2009 .",positive,"[('the second quarter of 2010', 'DATE'), ('Raute', 'ORG'), ('EUR 123,000', 'ORG'), ('EUR 1.5 million', 'MONEY'), ('the same period of', 'DATE'), ('2009', 'DATE')]"
"$DGI technical alerts: Gilligan's Island Buy Setup, Stochastic Buy Signal, Lizard Bullish, Hammer Candlestick, Wid... http://stks.co/c29Nu",positive,"[('DGI', 'PERSON'), ('Gilligan', 'PERSON'), ('Island Buy Setup', 'ORG'), ('Stochastic Buy Signal', 'ORG'), ('Lizard Bullish', 'PERSON'), ('Hammer Candlestick', 'PERSON')]"
"The record date for dividend distribution is March 14 , 2008 .",neutral,"[('March 14 , 2008', 'DATE')]"
( I&H ) in a move to enhance growth .,positive,"[('I&H', 'ORG')]"
"The EBRD is using its own funds to provide a 21.6 million A loan while the B portion of 10 million Euros has been syndicated to two Finnish commercial banks , Nordea Bank Finland Plc 7.7 million Euros and Pohjola Bank Plc 2.3 million Euros .",neutral,"[('EBRD', 'ORG'), ('21.6 million', 'CARDINAL'), ('10 million', 'CARDINAL'), ('Euros', 'PERSON'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Finnish', 'NORP'), ('Nordea Bank Finland Plc', 'ORG'), ('7.7 million', 'CARDINAL'), ('Euros', 'ORG'), ('Pohjola Bank Plc', 'ORG'), ('2.3 million', 'CARDINAL')]"
"Stockholm , 3 March 2011 About Cybercom The Cybercom Group is a high-tech consultancy that offers global sourcing for end-to-end solutions .",neutral,"[('Stockholm', 'GPE'), ('3 March 2011', 'DATE'), ('Cybercom The Cybercom Group', 'ORG')]"
He said he has been losing five families a month to the economy as many make alternative arrangements to save money .,negative,"[('five', 'CARDINAL')]"
"MILAN ( AFX ) - The Italian shipping group Grimaldi has increased its stake in the Finnish company Finnlines to 35.4 pct from the 30.5 pct held in June , according to news agency ANSA .",neutral,"[('MILAN', 'ORG'), ('AFX', 'ORG'), ('Italian', 'NORP'), ('Grimaldi', 'ORG'), ('Finnish', 'NORP'), ('Finnlines', 'NORP'), ('35.4', 'CARDINAL'), ('30.5', 'CARDINAL'), ('June', 'DATE'), ('ANSA', 'ORG')]"
"Commenting on the deal , Shane Lennon , SVP of Marketing & Product Development at GyPSii said : ?",neutral,"[('Shane Lennon', 'PERSON'), ('SVP of Marketing & Product Development', 'ORG')]"
"External net sales from the printing business fell by 43.7 % , partly due to the termination of the printing contract between Ilkka-Yhtyma 's printing house I-print Oy and sector player HSS Media AB in December 2009 and the fall in printing prices .",neutral,"[('43.7 %', 'PERCENT'), (""Ilkka-Yhtyma 's"", 'ORG'), ('HSS Media AB', 'ORG'), ('December 2009', 'DATE')]"
"The group intends to relocate warehouse and office space in Loudeac and Saint Marcel to Morvillars , in the east of the country , where it already operates a hook manufacturing and distribution unit .",neutral,"[('Loudeac', 'GPE'), ('Saint Marcel', 'GPE'), ('Morvillars', 'NORP')]"
"The firm is headquartered in Vantaa , southern Finland and has 16 employees .",neutral,"[('Vantaa', 'GPE'), ('Finland', 'GPE'), ('16', 'CARDINAL')]"
"At 1.33 pm , the OMX Helsinki 25 was 0.30 pct lower at 2,463.67 and the OMX Helsinki was down 0.37 pct at 8,537.42 on volume of 256 mln eur .",neutral,"[('1.33 pm', 'TIME'), ('the OMX Helsinki 25', 'ORG'), ('0.30', 'CARDINAL'), ('2,463.67', 'CARDINAL'), ('the OMX Helsinki', 'ORG'), ('0.37', 'CARDINAL'), ('8,537.42', 'CARDINAL'), ('256', 'CARDINAL')]"
"We are honored to be recognized by Gartner as a specialist in Business Process Modeling and Analysis , in the company of many of the largest software vendors in the world .",positive,"[('Gartner', 'ORG'), ('Business Process Modeling and', 'ORG'), ('Analysis', 'ORG')]"
"Westpac Banking Corp - Is to issue a benchmark , 3 year FRN deal in Euros .",neutral,"[('Westpac Banking Corp - Is', 'ORG'), ('3 year', 'DATE'), ('Euros', 'GPE')]"
"Includes company and brand share data by category , as well as distribution channel data .",neutral,[]
For the new shares subscribed with stock options all shareholder rights commence from the date on which they are entered into the Trade Register .,neutral,"[('the Trade Register', 'ORG')]"
$AAPL price momentum weakening going into the close.,negative,[]
Through the acquisition Solteq will expand its solutions offering by Microsoft 's Dynamics business software products .,positive,"[('Solteq', 'PERSON'), ('Microsoft', 'ORG')]"
"The company 's profit totaled Ls 134,700 .",neutral,"[('Ls 134,700', 'ORG')]"
"LEED is an internationally recognized green building certification system , developed by the U.S. Green Building Council .",neutral,"[('LEED', 'PERSON'), ('the U.S. Green Building Council', 'ORG')]"
"However , its market share shrank to 47.59 per cent from 48 per cent a year earlier .",negative,"[('47.59 per cent', 'MONEY'), ('48 per cent', 'MONEY'), ('a year earlier', 'DATE')]"
TalkTalk hires BAE Systems to investigate cyber attack,negative,"[('TalkTalk', 'CARDINAL'), ('BAE Systems', 'ORG')]"
Looks like its booking a one way ticket to its 40 week MA near 50. Losing 10 week here $LULU http://chart.ly/7xb9h9b,neutral,"[('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('40 week', 'DATE'), ('MA', 'PERSON'), ('50', 'DATE'), ('Losing 10 week', 'DATE'), ('LULU', 'PERSON')]"
"FTSE led lower by M&S, GlaxoSmithKline",negative,"[('FTSE', 'ORG'), ('M&S', 'ORG'), ('GlaxoSmithKline', 'PERSON')]"
The exercise price of the option will be based on Safran Software Solutions ' license and maintenance sales as well as the result of the company .,neutral,"[(""Safran Software Solutions '"", 'ORG')]"
Full-year operating result for 2008 was 3.6 million negative .,negative,"[('Full-year', 'DATE'), ('2008', 'DATE'), ('3.6 million', 'CARDINAL')]"
"The company said production volumes so far indicate the circuit is capable of the targeted output rate of 60,000 tonnes per day , or 22 million tonnes a year .",neutral,"[('60,000 tonnes', 'QUANTITY'), ('22 million tonnes', 'QUANTITY')]"
"Jun. 25 , 2008 ( Boy Genius Report delivered by Newstex ) -- The Nokia ( NYSE : NOK ) N78 , huh ?",neutral,"[('Jun. 25 , 2008', 'DATE'), ('NYSE', 'ORG'), ('NOK', 'ORG'), ('N78', 'ORG')]"
"`` We have come out with a decision which is based on our preliminary economic , operational and environmental findings , '' Karvinen said .",neutral,"[('Karvinen', 'PERSON')]"
"The new majority owners of Aspocomp Thailand Co. , Ltd are certain private persons belonging to immediate circle of Aspocomp 's present Joint Venture partner , Saha Pathana Inter-Holding Plc. .",neutral,"[('Aspocomp Thailand Co. , Ltd', 'ORG'), ('Aspocomp', 'LOC'), ('Joint Venture', 'ORG'), ('Saha Pathana Inter-Holding Plc', 'PERSON')]"
"Some 3.8 mln euro ( $ 5.2 mln ) of the base acquisition price will be paid in cash and the rest through a subscription offering of a total of 850,000 new Ixonos shares .",neutral,"[('Some 3.8 mln euro', 'QUANTITY'), ('$ 5.2 mln', 'MONEY'), ('850,000', 'CARDINAL'), ('Ixonos', 'ORG')]"
"Established in 1987 , the SRV Group is a private Finnish construction concern with operations in Finland , the Baltic countries and Russia .",neutral,"[('1987', 'DATE'), ('the SRV Group', 'ORG'), ('Finnish', 'NORP'), ('Finland', 'GPE'), ('Baltic', 'LOC'), ('Russia', 'GPE')]"
The business section also includes Ahlstrom 's sustainability report .,neutral,"[('Ahlstrom', 'ORG')]"
"+£lemiste City is the environment for a knowledge-based economy providing work for 3,300 people with the total turnover of its companies amounting to EEK 5.4 bn , '' said +£lo P+ñrnits , chairman of the supervisory board of +£lemiste City and Mainor .",neutral,"[('3,300', 'CARDINAL'), ('5.4', 'CARDINAL'), ('the supervisory board of', 'ORG'), ('Mainor', 'ORG')]"
Jacobs has been supporting Storengy 's investment of developing storage sites since 2006 as owner 's engineer .,neutral,"[('Jacobs', 'ORG'), ('Storengy', 'ORG'), ('2006', 'DATE')]"
"The company had earlier said that it was considering different strategic options for the struggling low-cost mobile operator , including a divestment of its holding .",neutral,[]
"Sainsbury's, Asda, Tesco and Morrisons will all cut petrol prices as oil falls ...",negative,"[('Sainsbury', 'ORG'), ('Asda', 'ORG'), ('Tesco', 'ORG'), ('Morrisons', 'PERSON')]"
Barclays sells benchmark indices unit to Bloomberg,positive,"[('Bloomberg', 'GPE')]"
Operating profit in the fourth quarter fell to EUR33m from EUR39m a year earlier .,neutral,"[('the fourth quarter', 'DATE'), ('a year earlier', 'DATE')]"
Finnish forestry company UPM-Kymmene and waste management company Lassila & Tikanoja said on Jan. 30 they were planning to produce ethanol and energy from commercial and industrial waste .,neutral,"[('Finnish', 'NORP'), ('UPM-Kymmene', 'ORG'), ('Lassila & Tikanoja', 'ORG'), ('Jan. 30', 'DATE')]"
"ISMS does not disclose its financial results , the daily said .",neutral,[]
"The contract covers the manufacturing , surface-treatment and installation of the steel structures .",neutral,[]
Finnish metal industry solutions supplier Outotec Oyj net profit rose to 50.4 mln euro ( $ 72.5 mln ) for the first nine months of 2007 from 20.1 mln euro ( $ 28.9 mln ) for the same period of 2006 .,positive,"[('Finnish', 'NORP'), ('Outotec Oyj', 'PERSON'), ('50.4 mln', 'MONEY'), ('$ 72.5 mln', 'MONEY'), ('the first nine months of 2007', 'DATE'), ('20.1 mln euro', 'MONEY'), ('$ 28.9 mln', 'MONEY'), ('the same period of', 'DATE'), ('2006', 'DATE')]"
"Under the deal , Know IT will pay SEK90m ( USD12 .8 m-EUR8 .6 m ) in cash and stock .",neutral,"[('USD12 .8 m-EUR8', 'ORG')]"
"$AAPL 50DMA turned up, MACD crossover a half-a-hair away on the weekly. EOD break out likely.",positive,"[('$AAPL 50DMA', 'MONEY'), ('weekly', 'DATE'), ('EOD', 'ORG')]"
Protalix has $ 42 million in cash and no sales .,neutral,"[('Protalix', 'ORG'), ('$ 42 million', 'MONEY')]"
That bearish outside day Tuesday is significant. 200 day resistance still intact. just my opinion $SDS http://chart.ly/2bey48t,negative,"[('day Tuesday', 'DATE'), ('200 day', 'DATE'), ('SDS', 'ORG')]"
All rights reserved .,neutral,[]
"It will be operated by Nokia , and supported by its Nokia NetAct network and service management system .",neutral,"[('Nokia', 'ORG'), ('Nokia', 'ORG')]"
"Mr Priit Kasak , Balti Metsamasina 's owner , said the Rakvere-based company wishes to increase Valmet 's market share from 27 % to a third in a couple of years .",positive,"[('Priit Kasak', 'PERSON'), (""Balti Metsamasina 's"", 'ORG'), ('Rakvere', 'ORG'), ('Valmet', 'ORG'), ('27 %', 'PERCENT'), ('a third', 'CARDINAL'), ('a couple of years', 'DATE')]"
Shire Sees Baxalta Deal Closing as Expected After New Rules,positive,"[('Shire Sees Baxalta Deal Closing as', 'ORG')]"
Sainsbury CFO Rogers to Replace Home Retail CEO Walden,neutral,[]
"Marathon now has a 4.6 percent stake in PLX , it said , according to Bloomberg .",neutral,"[('4.6 percent', 'PERCENT'), ('PLX', 'ORG'), ('Bloomberg', 'GPE')]"
"Simmons Elected DCUC Chairman PORTSMOUTH , N.H.-Gordon A. Simmons , CEO of Service Credit Union , has been elected chairman of the Defense Credit Union Council for the 2007-2008 term .",neutral,"[('N.H.-Gordon A. Simmons', 'PERSON'), ('Service Credit Union', 'ORG'), ('the Defense Credit Union Council', 'ORG'), ('2007-2008', 'DATE')]"
Sanoma News ' advertising sales decreased by 22 % during the year .,negative,"[(""Sanoma News '"", 'ORG'), ('22 %', 'PERCENT'), ('the year', 'DATE')]"
Pharmaceutical market in Czech Republic Global Research & Data Services published recently a market analysis about the pharmaceutical markets in Czech Republic .,neutral,"[('Czech Republic Global Research & Data Services', 'ORG'), ('Czech Republic', 'GPE')]"
"Finnish construction company YIT is reducing the number of start-ups of market-financed residential units in 2007 to about 2,300 from the previously announced 2,700 .",neutral,"[('Finnish', 'NORP'), ('YIT', 'ORG'), ('2007', 'DATE'), ('about 2,300', 'CARDINAL'), ('2,700', 'CARDINAL')]"
Cash Flow from Operations for the most recent quarter also reached a eight year low .,neutral,"[('Operations', 'ORG'), ('the most recent quarter', 'DATE'), ('eight year', 'DATE')]"
"TietoEnator was down 1.13 pct to 18.38 , extending recent lows after last week 's second-quarter report , dealers said .",negative,"[('1.13', 'CARDINAL'), ('18.38', 'CARDINAL'), (""last week 's"", 'DATE'), ('second-quarter', 'DATE')]"
The maritime administration said the ships had ignored warnings about the icy conditions .,negative,[]
Synergy Pharma Soars 67% Today On Positive Phase 3 Results $SGYP http://stks.co/j2awg,positive,"[('Synergy Pharma Soars', 'PERSON'), ('67%', 'PERCENT'), ('Today', 'DATE')]"
"Making matters more difficult , the company said it has been grappling with higher oil and gas prices , which have pushed up the cost of energy , raw materials and transportation .",negative,[]
"$VRTX Vertex. Monthly -lower hi/lower lo,  Long term uptrend intract so far",positive,"[('Monthly', 'DATE')]"
Financial details were not disclosed .,neutral,[]
"These include software development for internet and mobile telephone content , communications , value-added software , financial services , security applications , systems integration and electronics , '' EBRD informed .",neutral,"[('EBRD', 'PERSON')]"
"YIT lodged counter claims against Neste Oil totaling some EUR25m , primarily based on work carried out under the contract and additional costs incurred due to prolongation of the project .",neutral,"[('YIT', 'ORG'), ('Neste Oil', 'PERSON')]"
Should You Follow Berkshire Hathaway Into Apple Stock?,neutral,[]
The total amount of subscription prices was recorded in the fund for invested non-restricted equity .,neutral,[]
"$TSLA 5th wave down on the 1 hour chart, hammer candle developing, close to 200 sma, might be a good spot for calls",positive,"[('5th', 'ORDINAL'), ('the 1 hour', 'TIME'), ('200', 'CARDINAL')]"
"Strongest growth was seen in the new markets in Russia , the Czech Republic , and Slovakia .",positive,"[('Russia', 'GPE'), ('the Czech Republic', 'GPE'), ('Slovakia', 'GPE')]"
The tower 's engineers have created an 18 degree westward lean - four times the inclination on the Leaning Tower of Pisa - using diagrid structures that are aligned geometrically using Tekla Structures BIM ( Building Information Modeling ) software .,neutral,"[('18 degree westward', 'QUANTITY'), ('four', 'CARDINAL'), ('the Leaning Tower of Pisa -', 'FAC'), ('Tekla Structures BIM', 'PERSON'), ('Building Information Modeling', 'ORG')]"
"Amer , which bought Salomon from adidas in October , said the job cuts are aimed at boosting competitiveness .",neutral,"[('Salomon', 'ORG'), ('October', 'DATE')]"
"Acando AB ( ACANB SS ) fell 8.9 percent to 13.35 kronor , the lowest close since Dec. 11 .",negative,"[('Acando AB', 'ORG'), ('ACANB SS', 'ORG'), ('8.9 percent', 'PERCENT'), ('13.35 kronor', 'MONEY'), ('Dec. 11', 'DATE')]"
"With the measures , Suominen Corporation aims to ensure the competitiveness of the Flexible Packaging business in the long term .",positive,"[('Suominen Corporation', 'ORG')]"
"@IfHeDiesHeDies: @Bullhorn334: $ZNGA shorts are getting nervous""""",positive,"[('ZNGA', 'PERSON')]"
The financial statements release will be available after publishing on the Company 's internet pages at www.cargotec.com .,neutral,"[('Company', 'ORG')]"
"The world of glass is coming to Egypt and we invite Visitors from all around the world to attend Glass World Exhibition 2009 , Register Now at www.glassworldex.com",neutral,"[('Egypt', 'GPE'), ('Glass World Exhibition 2009', 'ORG'), ('Register Now', 'ORG')]"
"Comparable operating profit totaled EUR 4.7 mn , down from EUR 5.1 mn in the corresponding period in 2005 , representing 7.4 % of net sales .",negative,"[('EUR', 'ORG'), ('4.7', 'CARDINAL'), ('EUR', 'ORG'), ('2005', 'DATE'), ('7.4 %', 'PERCENT')]"
"Most of the raw materials come from Europe and the US and are paid in euros or US dollars , while sales take place in rubles .",neutral,"[('Europe', 'LOC'), ('US', 'GPE'), ('US', 'GPE')]"
"A maximum of 666,104 new shares can further be subscribed for by exercising B options under the 2004 stock option plan .",neutral,"[('666,104', 'CARDINAL'), ('2004', 'DATE')]"
It inspects the companys strategic strengths and weaknesses .,neutral,[]
No planned closing date was provided .,neutral,[]
"The Lemminkainen Group , headquartered in Helsinki , Finland operates in all sectors of the construction industry : civil engineering , building contracting , technical building services and the building materials industry .",neutral,"[('The Lemminkainen Group', 'ORG'), ('Helsinki', 'GPE'), ('Finland', 'GPE')]"
The implementation of the deal is subject to the approval by the Finnish Competition Authority .,neutral,"[('the Finnish Competition Authority', 'ORG')]"
"Microsoft also churned up its courtship , agreeing to use the Navteq mapping service , which is offered by a company Nokia bought for $ 8.1 billion a few years ago .",positive,"[('Microsoft', 'ORG'), ('Navteq', 'ORG'), ('Nokia', 'ORG'), ('$ 8.1 billion', 'MONEY'), ('a few years ago', 'DATE')]"
The GeoSolutions team further provides an intriguing new technology combining GPS and Mobile-based technologies together with Internet-based social networking .,neutral,"[('GeoSolutions', 'ORG'), ('Mobile', 'GPE')]"
"The 3C Expo is a signature show in Dongguan , which is supported by the Dongguan Municipal Government every year , featuring computer accessories , software , communication and network products .",neutral,"[('Dongguan', 'GPE'), ('the Dongguan Municipal Government', 'ORG'), ('every year', 'DATE')]"
Pharmaceuticals - Poland This brand-new market analysis gives a clear overview of the actual situation and future outlook of the pharmaceutical market in Poland .,neutral,"[('Poland', 'GPE')]"
"Trading in the new shares , which have right to dividends and other distributions of funds , will start on the exchange in Helsinki tomorrow .",neutral,"[('Helsinki', 'GPE'), ('tomorrow', 'DATE')]"
The dual-fuel engines of the vessel can operate on liquefied natural gas LNG with low emissions .,neutral,"[('LNG', 'ORG')]"
"- Among other Finnish shares traded in the US , Stora Enso closed 0.33 pct lower at 12.11 eur , UPM-Kymmene was up 0.28 pct at 18.10 eur , and Metso was down 0.13 pct at 31.06 eur .",neutral,"[('Finnish', 'NORP'), ('US', 'GPE'), ('Stora Enso', 'PERSON'), ('0.33', 'CARDINAL'), ('12.11', 'CARDINAL'), ('UPM-Kymmene', 'ORG'), ('0.28', 'CARDINAL'), ('18.10', 'CARDINAL'), ('Metso', 'ORG'), ('0.13', 'CARDINAL'), ('31.06', 'CARDINAL')]"
"In addition to the presentations held by President & CEO Kai Telanne and CFO Tuomas Itkonen , participants will have an opportunity to discuss with other members of the company 's management .",neutral,"[('President &', 'ORG'), ('Kai Telanne', 'PERSON'), ('CFO Tuomas Itkonen', 'ORG')]"
"The change in holdings in accordance with Chapter 2 , Section 9 of the Finnish Securities Markets Act is described below .",neutral,"[('Chapter 2 , Section 9', 'LAW'), ('the Finnish Securities Markets Act', 'ORG')]"
"With CapMan as a partner , we will be able to further develop our business and continue to focus on providing quality restaurant services for our customers , '' says Christopher Wynne , CEO of Papa John 's Russia .",positive,"[('Christopher Wynne', 'PERSON'), (""Papa John 's"", 'PERSON'), ('Russia', 'GPE')]"
The cranes would be installed onboard two freighters ordered by Singaporean ship owner Masterbulk .,neutral,"[('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Singaporean', 'NORP'), ('Masterbulk', 'PERSON')]"
The business to be divested generates consolidated net sales of EUR 60 million annually and currently has some 640 employees .,neutral,"[('EUR 60 million', 'MONEY'), ('annually', 'DATE'), ('some 640', 'CARDINAL')]"
"ADPnews - Feb 5 , 2010 - Finnish real estate investor Sponda Oyj HEL : SDA1V said today that it slipped to a net loss of EUR 81.5 million USD 11.8 m in 2009 from a profit of EUR 29.3 million in 2008 .",neutral,"[('Finnish', 'NORP'), ('Sponda Oyj', 'PERSON'), ('today', 'DATE'), ('EUR 81.5 million', 'MONEY'), ('2009', 'DATE'), ('EUR 29.3 million', 'MONEY'), ('2008', 'DATE')]"
"The company , which has EUR2 .8 bn in assets , counts among its five largest shareholders Finnish insurers Ilmarinen 4.34 % and Varma 0.70 % , as well as the Finnish state pension fund VER 0.61 % .",neutral,"[('EUR2', 'ORG'), ('five', 'CARDINAL'), ('Finnish', 'NORP'), ('Ilmarinen', 'ORG'), ('4.34 %', 'PERCENT'), ('Varma', 'GPE'), ('0.70 %', 'PERCENT'), ('Finnish', 'NORP'), ('VER 0.61 %', 'ORG')]"
"In addition , a further 29 employees can be laid off until further notice and the whole workforce can be laid off for short periods if needed .",neutral,"[('29', 'CARDINAL')]"
@chessNwine: $IWM 30-Minute Chart. Small caps threatening descending triangle breakdown under $110.20.  http://stks.co/r0KKm,negative,"[('IWM 30-Minute Chart', 'LAW'), ('110.20', 'MONEY')]"
CORPORATE IT UPDATE - ( C ) 1995-2009 M2 COMMUNICATIONS LTD Finnish technology group Teleste Corporation ( OMX Helsinki : TLT1V ) reported on Wednesday ( 4 February ) an operating profit of EUR5 .6 m on net sales of EUR108 .7 m for the year 2008 .,neutral,"[('1995-', 'DATE'), ('2009', 'DATE'), ('M2 COMMUNICATIONS LTD Finnish', 'ORG'), ('Teleste Corporation', 'ORG'), ('Wednesday', 'DATE'), ('4 February', 'DATE'), ('EUR108', 'NORP'), ('the year 2008', 'DATE')]"
"Stockholm-based Nordea Bank ( STO : NDA ) said yesterday it had hired Casper von Koskull to lead its corporate merchant banking and capital markets unit , effective 1 September .",neutral,"[('Stockholm', 'GPE'), ('Nordea Bank', 'ORG'), ('STO', 'ORG'), ('NDA', 'ORG'), ('yesterday', 'DATE'), ('Casper von Koskull', 'PERSON'), ('1 September', 'DATE')]"
The total need for staff cuts corresponds to about 300 man-years .,negative,"[('about 300', 'CARDINAL')]"
Finnish fibers and plastic products maker Suominen Corporation said its net loss narrowed to 1.6 mln euro $ 2.0 mln in the first nine months of 2006 from 2.16 mln euro $ 2.7 mln in the same period of 2005 .,positive,"[('Finnish', 'NORP'), ('Suominen Corporation', 'ORG'), ('1.6 mln', 'QUANTITY'), ('2.0', 'MONEY'), ('the first nine months of 2006', 'DATE'), ('2.16 mln', 'MONEY'), ('$ 2.7 mln', 'MONEY'), ('the same period of', 'DATE'), ('2005', 'DATE')]"
CompaniesFresnillo shares jump 8% as silver price breaks $21,positive,"[('CompaniesFresnillo', 'ORG'), ('8%', 'PERCENT'), ('21', 'MONEY')]"
Bluewin Security is available as a monthly subscription .,neutral,"[('Bluewin Security', 'PERSON'), ('monthly', 'DATE')]"
"Operating profit was EUR 11.4 mn , up from EUR 7.5 mn .",positive,"[('EUR', 'ORG'), ('11.4', 'CARDINAL'), ('EUR', 'ORG'), ('7.5', 'CARDINAL')]"
Finnish Raisio ( Diagnostics ) is launching new DNA-based quick tests to ensure the safety of food .,positive,"[('Finnish Raisio ( Diagnostics', 'ORG')]"
The non-recurring costs caused to Talentum 's Premedia business area by the restructuring will amount to 2.0 mln euro $ 2.7 mln and will be included in the company 's financial results for the second quarter of 2007 .,neutral,"[('Talentum', 'ORG'), ('Premedia', 'ORG'), ('2.0 mln', 'QUANTITY'), ('2.7', 'MONEY'), ('the second quarter of 2007', 'DATE')]"
"Finnish software developer Basware Oyj said on November 30 , 2006 its U.S. subsidiary Basware , Inc. won an order to provide software for contract lifecycle management to an unnamed U.S. medical technology company .",positive,"[('Finnish', 'NORP'), ('Basware Oyj', 'PERSON'), ('November 30 , 2006', 'DATE'), ('U.S.', 'GPE'), ('Basware , Inc.', 'ORG'), ('U.S.', 'GPE')]"
The chain is to unite 45-50 centres by the end of 2008 .,neutral,"[('45-50', 'CARDINAL'), ('the end of 2008', 'DATE')]"
"The important thing now is to keep the bank 's existing 15,000 customers .",neutral,"[('15,000', 'CARDINAL')]"
The prices of stainless steel also rose in Europe .,neutral,"[('Europe', 'LOC')]"
"In Sweden , Gallerix accumulated SEK denominated sales were down 1 % and EUR denominated sales were up 11 % .",neutral,"[('Sweden', 'GPE'), ('1 %', 'PERCENT'), ('EUR', 'ORG'), ('11 %', 'PERCENT')]"
$ISRG - ISRG Short - http://stks.co/f1vVU http://stks.co/c1qrm,negative,"[('$ISRG - ISRG Short - http://stks.co/f1vVU', 'MONEY')]"
$DARA breaking out,positive,"[('DARA', 'PERSON')]"
"A total of 38,244 new Citycon shares with a nominal value of EUR 1.35 per share were subscribed on 19 April exercising the A-B-C options based on the company 's stock option plan 1999 .",neutral,"[('38,244', 'CARDINAL'), ('Citycon', 'ORG'), ('EUR', 'ORG'), ('19 April', 'DATE'), ('1999', 'DATE')]"
$AAPL I'm sure those short are holding their breath hoping for a miracle. lol,positive,[]
`` Management decided at the end of 2005 to increase cathode copper capacity .,neutral,"[('`` Management', 'ORG'), ('the end of 2005', 'DATE')]"
Image data produced by the browser at the phone server is converted into a bitmapped image that is sent to the handset for display . '',neutral,[]
Shire says internal synergy goals from Baxalta deal higher,positive,"[('Shire', 'ORG'), ('Baxalta', 'ORG')]"
One of the largest projects of the magazine division of SanomaWSOY - Sanoma Magazines International in 2006 became launch of the Russian magazine Gloriya .,neutral,"[('One', 'CARDINAL'), ('SanomaWSOY - Sanoma Magazines International', 'ORG'), ('2006', 'DATE'), ('Russian', 'NORP'), ('Gloriya', 'ORG')]"
Finnish airline Finnair is starting the temporary layoffs of cabin crews in February 2010 .,neutral,"[('Finnish', 'NORP'), ('Finnair', 'ORG'), ('February 2010', 'DATE')]"
The sellers were the founders of the company .,neutral,[]
"Foodservice and consumer goods markets are served by approximately 13,000 people in 54 manufacturing units and several sales offices in 33 countries .",neutral,"[('approximately 13,000', 'CARDINAL'), ('54', 'CARDINAL'), ('33', 'CARDINAL')]"
"The acquisition does not have to be from the frozen foods or fish sector , as long as it has synergies with L+ñnnen Tehtaat 's other businesses .",neutral,"[('L+ñnnen', 'PRODUCT')]"
$GNRC finding support at its 10-day line so far.,positive,"[('10-day', 'DATE')]"
"Under the transaction agreement , Metsaliitto will purchase 24.7 % of Metsa-Botnia 's shares from UPM and 3 % from M-real .",neutral,"[('Metsaliitto', 'PERSON'), ('24.7 %', 'PERCENT'), (""Metsa-Botnia 's"", 'GPE'), ('UPM', 'ORG'), ('3 %', 'PERCENT')]"
"Britain's FTSE falls back with Ashtead, commodities under pressure",negative,"[('Britain', 'GPE'), ('FTSE', 'ORG')]"
Sales by Seppala diminished by 6 per cent .,neutral,"[('Seppala', 'PERSON'), ('6 per cent', 'MONEY')]"
$BBRY bye bye Sammy. Hello BB. Sounds like we'll see some green tomorrow.,positive,"[('Sammy', 'PERSON'), ('BB', 'GPE'), ('tomorrow', 'DATE')]"
"As capacity was cut with 1.4 % , the passenger load factor was down 7.8 percentage points .",negative,"[('1.4 %', 'PERCENT'), ('7.8', 'CARDINAL')]"
"Rockwell Collins is a provider of flight deck , cabin and information management solutions for business aircraft operators .",neutral,"[('Rockwell Collins', 'PERSON')]"
"The floor area of the Yliopistonrinne project will be 7,900 sq m and the building 's gross area will total 12,800 sq m. A total 25.1 % of the facilities have been let .",neutral,"[('Yliopistonrinne', 'GPE'), ('7,900', 'CARDINAL'), ('12,800', 'CARDINAL'), ('25.1 %', 'PERCENT')]"
$NFLX VISION : short term consolidation then movement higher http://stks.co/j05uu,positive,"[('NFLX', 'ORG')]"
"Theodosopoulos said Tellabs could be of value to Nokia Siemens or Nortel given its `` leading supply status '' with Verizon , along with high-growth products .",positive,"[('Tellabs', 'NORP'), ('Nokia Siemens', 'ORG'), ('Nortel', 'ORG'), ('Verizon', 'GPE')]"
"In his current position , Manty has worked since 1996 .",neutral,"[('Manty', 'PERSON'), ('since 1996', 'DATE')]"
With the new production plant the company would increase its capacity to meet the expected increase in demand and would improve the use of raw materials and therefore increase the production profitability .,positive,[]
Analyst Views: Astrazeneca shares have seen recent volatility; what will 2015 ...,negative,"[('2015', 'DATE')]"
Earnings per share ( EPS ) dropped to EUR 0.21 from EUR 0.31 .,neutral,"[('EPS', 'ORG'), ('EUR', 'ORG'), ('EUR 0.31', 'ORG')]"
"`` After the transaction , Tikkurila has no powder coatings-related operations , '' the company said .",neutral,"[('Tikkurila', 'PERSON')]"
"Are ARM Holdings plc, Domino's Pizza Group plc and ASOS plc 3 must-have growth stocks?",neutral,"[('ARM Holdings plc', 'ORG'), ('Domino', 'PERSON'), ('Pizza Group plc', 'ORG'), ('ASOS', 'ORG'), ('3', 'CARDINAL')]"
"Pearl Plaza LLC , the joint venture of SRV and Shanghai Industrial Investment Holdings Co Ltd , has concluded the investment decision on construction of the first phase of the shopping center in Saint Petersburg , Russia .",positive,"[('Pearl Plaza LLC', 'FAC'), ('SRV', 'ORG'), ('Shanghai Industrial Investment Holdings Co Ltd', 'ORG'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Saint Petersburg', 'GPE'), ('Russia', 'GPE')]"
The measures result from decreased demand in technical design and product information .,neutral,[]
"Finnish financial group Aktia reports operating profit of EUR 44.4 mn in January-September 2009 , up from EUR 37.3 mn in the corresponding period in 2008 .",positive,"[('Finnish', 'NORP'), ('Aktia', 'ORG'), ('EUR', 'ORG'), ('January-September 2009', 'DATE'), ('EUR', 'ORG'), ('37.3', 'CARDINAL'), ('2008', 'DATE')]"
"Key price to watch in $NFLX, off the previous double top reject, 218.23 http://stks.co/sIYn",negative,"[('NFLX', 'ORG'), ('218.23', 'CARDINAL'), ('http://stks.co/sIYn', 'PERSON')]"
Finnish glass technology company Glaston Oyj Abp net profit decreased to 2.6 mln euro ( $ 3.8 mln ) for the first nine months of 2007 from 7.8 mln euro ( $ 11.4 mln ) for the same period of 2006 .,neutral,"[('Finnish', 'NORP'), ('Glaston Oyj Abp', 'PERSON'), ('2.6 mln euro', 'QUANTITY'), ('$ 3.8 mln', 'MONEY'), ('the first nine months of 2007', 'DATE'), ('7.8 mln euro', 'QUANTITY'), ('$ 11.4 mln', 'MONEY'), ('the same period of', 'DATE'), ('2006', 'DATE')]"
City spirits sink after Diageo comes up short with sales slide,negative,"[('Diageo', 'PERSON')]"
Operating loss increased to EUR 17mn from a loss of EUR 10.8 mn in 2005 .,neutral,"[('17mn', 'ORDINAL'), ('EUR', 'ORG'), ('10.8', 'CARDINAL'), ('2005', 'DATE')]"
"ALEXANDRIA , Va. , June 7 -- Michael G. Williams of Newbury Park , Calif. , has developed a network device .",neutral,"[('ALEXANDRIA', 'GPE'), ('Va.', 'GPE'), ('June 7', 'DATE'), ('Michael G. Williams', 'PERSON'), ('Newbury Park', 'GPE'), ('Calif.', 'GPE')]"
Olvi has posted a strong set of figures for the first six months of this year .,positive,"[('Olvi', 'PERSON'), ('the first six months of this year', 'DATE')]"
StanChart and RBS struggle in Bank of England stress tests,negative,"[('StanChart', 'ORG'), ('RBS', 'ORG'), ('Bank of England', 'ORG')]"
"In the beginning of this year , Wartsila had secured an order to deliver four gas-fuelled main engines and propulsion machinery for the same vessel .",positive,"[('the beginning of this year', 'DATE'), ('Wartsila', 'GPE'), ('four', 'CARDINAL')]"
"In January-November 2009 , the group 's sales totalled EUR 7,801.7 mn , which was a drop of 12.6 % from the same period of 2008 .",negative,"[('January-November 2009', 'DATE'), ('EUR', 'ORG'), ('12.6 %', 'PERCENT'), ('the same period of 2008', 'DATE')]"
"GlaxoSmithKline targets growth across units, scraps ViiV IPO",positive,"[('GlaxoSmithKline', 'PERSON'), ('IPO', 'ORG')]"
BHP Billiton share price: Brazil to sue Samarco for Â£3.5bn,negative,"[('BHP Billiton', 'ORG'), ('Brazil', 'GPE'), ('Samarco', 'ORG')]"
"It comes complete with an LCD touch screen system for selection of your chosen function and prices start at around the pounds 4,805 mark .",neutral,"[('LCD', 'ORG')]"
Revenue in the quarter fell 8 percent to ( EURO ) 2.4 billion compared to a year earlier .,neutral,"[('the quarter', 'DATE'), ('8 percent', 'PERCENT'), ('2.4 billion', 'CARDINAL'), ('a year earlier', 'DATE')]"
"After the split , the company would have 26,885,540 Series A shares and 9,540,000 Series K shares .",neutral,"[('26,885,540', 'CARDINAL'), ('9,540,000', 'CARDINAL')]"
"A. Le Coq Special was developed for the bicentenary of the company and the trade mark , the brewer said .",neutral,"[('A. Le Coq Special', 'PERSON')]"
ArcelorMittal Chief Executive Officer Lakshmi Mittal has already cut output at some furnaces .,neutral,"[('ArcelorMittal', 'ORG'), ('Lakshmi Mittal', 'PERSON')]"
Operating profit fell to EUR 15.1 mn from EUR 24.6 mn in 2006 .,neutral,"[('EUR', 'ORG'), ('15.1', 'CARDINAL'), ('EUR 24.6', 'ORG'), ('2006', 'DATE')]"
The bridge is part of the highway 14 development project .,neutral,"[('14', 'CARDINAL')]"
"Kesko Agro Lietuva , the agricultural machinery and grain trader and another member of the Kesko Group , boosted its sales by 42.9 percent to 13.4 million euros , VAT inclusive .",positive,"[('Kesko Agro Lietuva', 'PERSON'), ('the Kesko Group', 'ORG'), ('42.9 percent', 'PERCENT'), ('13.4 million', 'CARDINAL'), ('VAT', 'ORG')]"
"( ADPnews ) - Dec 1 , 2009 - Finnish cutlery and hand tools maker Fiskars Oyj Abp ( HEL : FISAS ) said today that it will make redundant a total of 18 office and management staff members of its subsidiary Iittala Group Ltd. .",negative,"[('Finnish', 'NORP'), ('Fiskars Oyj Abp', 'PERSON'), ('HEL', 'ORG'), ('FISAS', 'ORG'), ('today', 'DATE'), ('18', 'CARDINAL'), ('Iittala Group Ltd.', 'ORG')]"
Metso Foundries Jyvaskyla Oy will discontinue production on this line by 30 September 2008 .,neutral,"[('Metso', 'ORG'), ('30 September 2008', 'DATE')]"
The sale price was not disclosed .,neutral,[]
"In February 2011 , new wording of Identity Documents Act that makes Mobile ID a state-approved electronic document as of February 1st 2011 entered into force .",neutral,"[('February 2011', 'DATE'), ('Identity Documents Act', 'LAW'), ('February 1st 2011', 'DATE')]"
"Antti Orkola , president of Kemira GrowHow 's Industrial Solutions unit , told Thomson Financial News the company has put off opening the mine as prices of phosphate have been ` quite depressed for a long time ' . '",negative,"[('Antti Orkola', 'ORG'), (""Kemira GrowHow 's"", 'ORG'), ('Industrial Solutions', 'ORG'), ('Thomson Financial News', 'ORG')]"
You 're not alone .,neutral,[]
"The sale of Savcor FACE to Cencorp will result in a profit or loss which can not yet be determined , owing to factors including the valuation of the consideration shares to be received and prevailing exchange rates .",neutral,"[('Savcor FACE to', 'ORG'), ('Cencorp', 'ORG')]"
The acquisition of +àlandsbanken Sverige in 2009 burdened the performance with EUR 3.0 mn .,neutral,"[('2009', 'DATE'), ('EUR', 'ORG')]"
It is the first application in the market for invoice and purchase requisition approval with a mobile device .,neutral,"[('first', 'ORDINAL')]"
